[
  {
    "id": "recwd5yAGwLV3AHWQ",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "authority, service delivery",
    "Subsection": "C",
    "Questions": [
      "reclGjy18Ovhszv3Y"
    ],
    "Question": "Can the City of Tulsa provide any service or facility?",
    "Questions copy": "Can the City of Tulsa provide any service or facility?",
    "Answer": "Yes, as long as it is \"for the common benefit or in the furtherance of any function performed by the city\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "recYkbEK2qJD5ydmW",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "taxes, income tax, elections",
    "Subsection": "D",
    "Questions": [
      "rec9DiQE6bgvPShgC"
    ],
    "Question": "How would an income tax be instituted in the City of Tulsa?",
    "Questions copy": "How would an income tax be instituted in the City of Tulsa?",
    "Answer": "Through an election question voted in by a majority of voters. As it stands, the City of Tulsa may collect income tax provided that such tax has \"been approved by a majority of the qualified electors of the City of Tulsa voting on the question at an election for the purpose of approving or disapproving of a proposed tax\". Also, it is possible for the State of Oklahoma to preempt such laws?",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "recjdb1KitBoItBXK",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "authority, taxes, sales tax, elections",
    "Subsection": "D",
    "Questions": [
      "recZs9CHqvBvKgwrm"
    ],
    "Question": "Can the City of Tulsa change the sales tax?",
    "Questions copy": "Can the City of Tulsa change the sales tax?",
    "Answer": "Through an election question voted in by a majority of voters. As it stands, the City of Tulsa may collect sales tax provided that such tax has \"been approved by a majority of the qualified electors of the City of Tulsa voting on the question at an election for the purpose of approving or disapproving of a proposed tax\". Also, it is possible for the State of Oklahoma to preempt such laws?",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "recVrEJgKdAMuw3rj",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "authority, fees, licensing fees",
    "Subsection": "E",
    "Questions": [
      "recUs51nsxk0gsqTN"
    ],
    "Question": "Can the City of Tulsa issue licensing fees for the purpose of revenue collection?",
    "Questions copy": "Can the City of Tulsa issue licensing fees for the purpose of revenue collection?",
    "Answer": "Yes.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "recFtDVSlpoSdA5As",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "authority, fees, licensing fees, regulation",
    "Subsection": "E",
    "Questions": [
      "reckS1G1iXA8aa7QN"
    ],
    "Question": "Can the City of Tulsa issue licensing fees for the purpose of regulation?",
    "Questions copy": "Can the City of Tulsa issue licensing fees for the purpose of regulation?",
    "Answer": "Yes.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "recO3HIAzQZHS5It4",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "authority, special assessments",
    "Subsection": "F",
    "Questions": [
      "recl88C1qi94azDuA"
    ],
    "Question": "Can the City of Tulsa levy and collect special assessments for benefits conferred?",
    "Questions copy": "Can the City of Tulsa levy and collect special assessments for benefits conferred?",
    "Answer": "Yes.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "recArHm2PkDyCUQqN",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "authority, debt, spending",
    "Subsection": "G",
    "Questions": [
      "recW8BI6yobVdgGbs"
    ],
    "Question": "Can the City of Tulsa incur debt?",
    "Questions copy": "Can the City of Tulsa incur debt?",
    "Answer": "Yes.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "recZ1UTclsoDNZfi3",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "jurisdiction, policy enforcement",
    "Subsection": "I",
    "Questions": [
      "recBgWfp1vnLa23DG"
    ],
    "Question": "Can the City of Tulsa enforce endorinances on property owned, leased, controlled, or supervised by the city that is outside of its corporate limits?",
    "Questions copy": "\"Can the City of Tulsa enforce endorinances on property owned, leased, controlled, or supervised by the city that is outside of its corporate limits?\"",
    "Answer": "Yes.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "recuyQc1kgq9Eu1Ot",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "jurisdiction, policy enforcement",
    "Subsection": "J",
    "Questions": [
      "recOA5ltx4YJJ69zq"
    ],
    "Question": "Can the City of Tulsa exercise jurisdiction over property that is outside of its corporate limits?",
    "Questions copy": "Can the City of Tulsa exercise jurisdiction over property that is outside of its corporate limits?",
    "Answer": "Yes, \"as authorized by the laws of Oklahoma\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "recAUo3LIJHz9Z9pm",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "governance, intergovernmental relations, collaboration",
    "Subsection": "K",
    "Questions": [
      "recnsxGmyRburNO4N"
    ],
    "Question": "Can the City of Tulsa enter into agreements with states other than Oklahoma?",
    "Questions copy": "Can the City of Tulsa enter into agreements with states other than Oklahoma?",
    "Answer": "Yes.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec9UUj4uejKJZNuu",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "governance, intergovernmental relations, interlocal, collaboration, State of Oklahoma, Federal Government, Private corporations, ppp,",
    "Subsection": "K",
    "Questions": [
      "rec8wvWFld0yEJnNU"
    ],
    "Question": "Who can the City of Tulsa enter into agreements with?",
    "Questions copy": "Who can the City of Tulsa enter into agreements with?",
    "Answer": "The City of Tulsa may \"enter into agreements with the State of Oklahoma; with another state or municipality; with any subdivision or agency thereof; with the federal government or any agency thereof; with private corporations, partnerships or individuals, or any combination thereof; and to exercise jointly all powers, privileges, and authority conferred upon the City of Tulsa by this amended Charter or by the laws of Oklahoma\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "reczHhaTuTmYMUW7n",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "authority, policy enforcement, waterports",
    "Subsection": "L",
    "Questions": [
      "recEBvpqZlB2vO3Aj"
    ],
    "Question": "What powers does the City of Tulsa have with respect to waterports?",
    "Questions copy": "What powers does the City of Tulsa have with respect to waterports?",
    "Answer": "The City of Tulsa may \"acquire, plan, establish, develop, construct, enlarge, improve, maintain, manage, equip, operate, regulate, and protect waterports, airports, and air navigation facilities within or without the corporate limits\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "recrDWfXM8TgrKqlC",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "authority, airports, air navigation",
    "Subsection": "L",
    "Questions": [
      "reciZl4VQxFZ5Pw3T"
    ],
    "Question": "What powers does the City of Tulsa have with respect to airports and air navigation facilities?",
    "Questions copy": "What powers does the City of Tulsa have with respect to airports and air navigation facilities?",
    "Answer": "The City of Tulsa may \"acquire, plan, establish, develop, construct, enlarge, improve, maintain, manage, equip, operate, regulate, and protect waterports, airports, and air navigation facilities within or without the corporate limits\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "recIJf44fLcjVyLNy",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "spending",
    "Subsection": "M",
    "Questions": [
      "rec8bb7qBEZ9UefNN"
    ],
    "Question": "What can the City of Tulsa appropriate and expend money for?",
    "Questions copy": "What can the City of Tulsa appropriate and expend money for?",
    "Answer": "The City of Tulsa may \"appropriate and expend money for any public purpose\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "recc3yIwRBWQvR2cn",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Suggestion": "After the answer, suggest learning more about zoning in Tulsa with a link to the page on zoning.",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "regulation, policy enforcement, land use",
    "Subsection": "N",
    "Questions": [
      "recYLfzqYlK5TjRVy"
    ],
    "Question": "Can the City of Tulsa restrict and regulate the use of land?",
    "Questions copy": "Can the City of Tulsa restrict and regulate the use of land?",
    "Answer": "Yes, the City of Tulsa may \"restrict and regulate the use and subdivision of land, to perform planning and zoning, and to establish by ordinance the procedures therefor\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec2GiJb29kOQAMIC",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Suggestion": "After the answer, suggest learning more about local questions, with a link to a page outlining that.",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "nuisance, policy enforcement",
    "Subsection": "O",
    "Questions": [
      "recDkJkgHxnqz33EP"
    ],
    "Question": "What can the City of Tulsa do to address nuisances?",
    "Questions copy": "What can the City of Tulsa do to address nuisances?",
    "Answer": "The City of Tulsa may \"abate nuisances of any kind\" as well as \"assess the expense thereof as a special tax against the land upon which the nuisance is located\". As of 2018, it has been clarified that the City of Tulsa \"may summarily abate a nuisance re-occuring on the same property under the same ownership within twenty-four (24) months of a previous nuisance abatement on that property\" as well as assess the expense thereof as a special tax against the land. This resulted from a 2017 vote through which 8,291 Tulsans voted in favor of this amendment against 2,123 Tulsans voting against.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3) - General Grant of Power"
  },
  {
    "id": "recRzV9GFHcQO0OA1",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Suggestion": "See Article VI for more",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "city council, districts, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "rec72PZRelFTGbiNs"
    ],
    "Question": "What is the composition of Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Questions copy": "What is the composition of Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Answer": "City Council is \"composed of nine (9) Councilors elected by districts\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1) - Creation and Function"
  },
  {
    "id": "recYO33OmVBH5yCjQ",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, city council, spending, salaries",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "rec4cV0uZuW1I6tWF"
    ],
    "Question": "What is the salary of a City Councilor in Tulsa?",
    "Questions copy": "What is the salary of a City Councilor in Tulsa?",
    "Answer": "$24,000 annually",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(2) - Salaries"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec0Qnoeo7RJZBVTE",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, city council, spending, salaries",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recWcMxNuRrmjrQcC"
    ],
    "Question": "Can Tulsa's City Council vote to change its own salary?",
    "Questions copy": "Can Tulsa's City Council vote to change its own salary?",
    "Answer": "No. Prior to December 1st, 2014, this was not the case. Tulsa's City Council could change their salary by majority vote to go into effect after \"the commencement of the term of office next succeeding the term in which the change is made and then only in the event such change was approved prior to the general election for the next succeeding term\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(2) - Salaries"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec6socomWn37C8Wo",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, city council, spending",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "rec4WnsrbE3WjjKIZ"
    ],
    "Question": "Are Tulsa's City Councilors reimbursed for expenses incurred in the performance of their duties?",
    "Questions copy": "Are Tulsa's City Councilors reimbursed for expenses incurred in the performance of their duties?",
    "Answer": "\"Councilors may be reimbursed for expenses incurred in the performance of their duties\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(2) - Salaries"
  },
  {
    "id": "recpk2Lp5gB9f28Yn",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, city council, meetings",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recwPqzzGCjWLKXoP"
    ],
    "Question": "What are the minimum number of meetings that Tulsa's City Council must hold?",
    "Questions copy": "What are the minimum number of meetings that Tulsa's City Council must hold?",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's City Council must hold at least two (2) meetings every month and these meetings must be held at City Hall.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3.1) - Meetings"
  },
  {
    "id": "recjdtdy7L7HfQjHU",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Suggestion": "Note that one exception to this is Civil Emergences (3.2) - \"After proclamation by the Mayor of a civil emergency by virtue of an armed conflict, civil disorder, or natural disaster, the Council may meet at any place within the corporate limits of the city in special session and without notice and consider such matters as necessary for the preservation of the public health, safety, and welfare during the period of the emergency\".",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, city council, meetings, special meetings",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recQ4Z9ieO76kxkMi"
    ],
    "Question": "Who can call a special meeting for Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Questions copy": "Who can call a special meeting for Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Answer": "The Mayor of Tulsa, the Chairman of the City Council, or one-third (1/3) of Tulsa's City Council may call special meetings. Written notice must be delivered to each City Councilor at least 24 hours prior to such special meeting. This notice must include the date, time, and place of the special meeting. This written notice can be served (a) electronically, (2) in-person, or (3) can be left at the usual place of residence of the City Councilor. Finally, only those subjects included in the written notice can be considered at special meetings.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3.1) - Meetings"
  },
  {
    "id": "recc09LDnpBCj6aSV",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Suggestion": "Note that one exception to this is Civil Emergences (3.2) - \"After proclamation by the Mayor of a civil emergency by virtue of an armed conflict, civil disorder, or natural disaster, the Council may meet at any place within the corporate limits of the city in special session and without notice and consider such matters as necessary for the preservation of the public health, safety, and welfare during the period of the emergency\".",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, city council, meetings, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "reca3D137tucbTiuV"
    ],
    "Question": "How much notice must be given to each City Councilor prior to a special meeting?",
    "Questions copy": "How much notice must be given to each City Councilor prior to a special meeting?",
    "Answer": "Written notice must be delivered to each City Councilor at least 24 hours prior to such special meeting. Written notice must include the date, time, and place of the special meeting. This written notice can be served (a) electronically, (2) in-person, or (3) can be left at the usual place of residence of the City Councilor. Only those subjects included in the written notice can be considered at special meetings. The Mayor of Tulsa, the Chairman of the City Council, or one-third (1/3) of Tulsa's City Council may call such special meetings. ",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3.1) - Meetings"
  },
  {
    "id": "recrCgNaRAZ9MkaXs",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Suggestion": "Note that one exception to this is Civil Emergences (3.2) - \"After proclamation by the Mayor of a civil emergency by virtue of an armed conflict, civil disorder, or natural disaster, the Council may meet at any place within the corporate limits of the city in special session and without notice and consider such matters as necessary for the preservation of the public health, safety, and welfare during the period of the emergency\".",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, city council, meetings, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recU7zzXDyx9CDJrS"
    ],
    "Question": "What must be included in special meeting notices to City Councilors?",
    "Questions copy": "What must be included in special meeting notices to City Councilors?",
    "Answer": "Written notice to City Councilors concerning special meetings must include the date, time, and place of the meeting. Written notice must be delivered to each City Councilor at least 24 hours prior to such special meeting. This written notice can be served (a) electronically, (2) in-person, or (3) can be left at the usual place of residence of the City Councilor. Only those subjects included in the written notice can be considered at special meetings. The Mayor of Tulsa, the Chairman of the City Council, or one-third (1/3) of Tulsa's City Council may call special meetings. ",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3.1) - Meetings"
  },
  {
    "id": "recL7Xjal2BSCbr3a",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Suggestion": "Note that one exception to this is Civil Emergences (3.2) - \"After proclamation by the Mayor of a civil emergency by virtue of an armed conflict, civil disorder, or natural disaster, the Council may meet at any place within the corporate limits of the city in special session and without notice and consider such matters as necessary for the preservation of the public health, safety, and welfare during the period of the emergency\".",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, city council, meetings, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recoXdSTcYeBgaFQ1"
    ],
    "Question": "Can subject matters not included in written notice to Tulsa's City Council be considered in special meetings?",
    "Questions copy": "Can subject matters not included in written notice to Tulsa's City Council be considered in special meetings?",
    "Answer": "No, only those subjects outlined in the written notice can be considered. Written notice must be delivered to each City Councilor at least 24 hours prior to such special meeting. Written notice must include the date, time, and place of the special meeting. This written notice can be served (a) electronically, (2) in-person, or (3) can be left at the usual place of residence of the City Councilor. The Mayor of Tulsa, the Chairman of the City Council, or one-third (1/3) of Tulsa's City Council may call such special meetings. ",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3.1) - Meetings"
  },
  {
    "id": "recViCls8CGR3SyGt",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Suggestion": " ",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, mayor-council relations, governance, civil emergency, meetings",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recKUtQmqzyICt2px"
    ],
    "Question": "Who can call a civil emergency in Tulsa?",
    "Questions copy": "Who can call a civil emergency in Tulsa?",
    "Answer": "The Mayor of Tulsa. During a Civil Emergency, City Council can meet for special meetings anywhere within the corporate limits of the City of Tulsa, without notice, and may consider \"matters as necessary for the preservation of the public health, safety, and welfare during the period of the emergency\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3.2) - Civil Emergencies"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec1HPb7olIu74sXv",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, city council, meetings",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recUgUnXQxPXkyOPy"
    ],
    "Question": "How do City Council meeting rules change during a civil emergency?",
    "Questions copy": "How do City Council meeting rules change during a civil emergency?",
    "Answer": "During a Civil Emergency, City Council can meet for special meetings anywhere within the corporate limits of the City of Tulsa, without notice, and may consider \"matters as necessary for the preservation of the public health, safety, and welfare during the period of the emergency\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3.2) - Civil Emergencies"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec79OfrV2ULMlw3O",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, governance, civil emergency, tulsa dictionary",
    "Questions": [
      "recXMslOU9IVA9375"
    ],
    "Question": "What is a civil emergency in Tulsa?",
    "Questions copy": "What is a civil emergency in Tulsa?",
    "Enterman": "Samuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "recSBg5R0pIJUUvl5",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, city council, meetings, governance, open meeting laws",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recIFNsGqXbgngSEq"
    ],
    "Question": "Are City Council meetings subject to open meeting laws?",
    "Questions copy": "Are City Council meetings subject to open meeting laws?",
    "Answer": "Yes.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(3.3) - Open Meetings"
  },
  {
    "id": "rechwFSnIGW1guiYQ",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "state of oklahoma, open meeting laws",
    "Questions": [
      "recQWNTioQTAzS9WA"
    ],
    "Question": "What are Oklahoma's open meeting laws?",
    "Questions copy": "What are Oklahoma's open meeting laws?",
    "Enterman": "Samuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "recYBwSExpE2a8oQS",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, city council, governance, employment",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recI3uF7NibyH8ZRH"
    ],
    "Question": "Can Tulsa's City Council employ persons to assist the Council in the performance of its duties?",
    "Questions copy": "Can Tulsa's City Council employ persons to assist the Council in the performance of its duties?",
    "Answer": "Yes, Tulsa's City Council \"may employ such persons as are necessary to assist the Council in the performance of its duties\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(4) - Rules"
  },
  {
    "id": "recHMKokNgWNxHPkR",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, city council, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "rec4tJc3UgHGkzDvB"
    ],
    "Question": "Who determines the rules and order of business of Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Questions copy": "Who determines the rules and order of business of Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's City Council \"shall determine and estavblish its own rules and order of business\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(4) - Rules"
  },
  {
    "id": "recnV3NExpaaQSwkB",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, city council, fines, meetings, disorderly conduct",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "reccTMBOeNv6A7ojy"
    ],
    "Question": "Can Tulsa's City Council fine its own members for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting?",
    "Questions copy": "Can Tulsa's City Council fine its own members for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting?",
    "Answer": "\"The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city. The vote of two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to impose a fine on a Councilor\"",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(4) - Rules"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec6dHvj2wAek4eAI",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, city council, fines, meetings,",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "rec3gVv0sol719CIg"
    ],
    "Question": "Can Tulsa's City Council fine its own members for violation of Council rules?",
    "Questions copy": "Can Tulsa's City Council fine its own members for violation of Council rules?",
    "Answer": "\"The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city. The vote of two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to impose a fine on a Councilor\"",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(4) - Rules"
  },
  {
    "id": "reci6BnEK0LzSvW2r",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, city council, fines, meetings, disorderly conduct",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "rec9WdE6TGWeb8smt"
    ],
    "Question": "Can Tulsa's City Council fine persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting?",
    "Questions copy": "Can Tulsa's City Council fine persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting?",
    "Answer": "\"The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city. The vote of two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to impose a fine on a Councilor\"",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(4) - Rules"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec9SA7mxbOe4me55",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, city council, fines, meetings",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recOcX2z6GYD1URAT"
    ],
    "Question": "Can Tulsa's City Council fine persons for violation of council rules?",
    "Questions copy": "Can Tulsa's City Council fine persons for violation of council rules?",
    "Answer": "\"The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city. The vote of two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to impose a fine on a Councilor\"",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(4) - Rules"
  },
  {
    "id": "recabVVIVAtXoBIlW",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, city council, fines, punishments",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recbvPA2CBoYJscfG"
    ],
    "Question": "How much can Tulsa's City Council fine its members or other persons for a single offense?",
    "Questions copy": "How much can Tulsa's City Council fine its members or other persons for a single offense?",
    "Answer": "$100 dollars. \"The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city. The vote of two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to impose a fine on a Councilor\"",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(4) - Rules"
  },
  {
    "id": "recY1i3fmYOSQI0Ef",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, city council, fines, punishments",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "rec7NZUk3vNDJrDQM"
    ],
    "Question": "How much of Tulsa's City Council does it take to impose a fine on a fellow City Councilor?",
    "Questions copy": "How much of Tulsa's City Council does it take to impose a fine on a fellow City Councilor?",
    "Answer": "Two-thirds of the entire City Council. When each of the nine seats are filled, this means six Councilors must vote to impose such fine. \"The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(4) - Rules"
  },
  {
    "id": "recKi8AtiNrxKjWOg",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, city council, chairman, vice chairman",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recDI9C1Q4m6rxeUS"
    ],
    "Question": "Who elects the Chairman and Vice Chairman of Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Questions copy": "Who elects the Chairman and Vice Chairman of Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's City Council elects their own Chairman and Vice Chairman. Further, the terms of such positions are determined by the Council. Duties can be assigned to the Chairman via charter amendment, ordinance, or rule of the Council. The Vice Chairman performs duties of the Chairman under conditions of the Chairman's absense.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(5) - Chairman"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec8jmKbcIDkI6PYA",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/22/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, city council, chairman",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "rec6AKLn5Mx88NOwM"
    ],
    "Question": "Who assigns duties to the Chairman of Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Questions copy": "Who assigns duties to the Chairman of Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's City Council assigns duties to the Chairman via charter amendment, ordinance, or rule of the Council. Further, Tulsa's City Council elects their own Chairman and Vice Chairman and the terms of such positions are determined by the Council. Finally, the Vice Chairman performs duties of the Chairman under conditions of the Chairman's absense.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(5) - Chairman"
  },
  {
    "id": "recsChAwABV0RmGTW",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/23/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, city council, subpoena,",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "rec2k8EIZMHW2OMh6"
    ],
    "Question": "Does Tulsa's City Council have the power to subpoena witnesses?",
    "Questions copy": "Does Tulsa's City Council have the power to subpoena witnesses?",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's City Council has \"the power to subpoena witnesses and require the production of records\" for the purposes of judgging the qualification of its members.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(6.1) - Judge of Qualifications"
  },
  {
    "id": "recEWQxLxiJSGetAu",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/23/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, city council, judge, qualifications",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recCESevPNO9OvkIe"
    ],
    "Question": "Who is the judge of the qualifications of Tulsa's City Councilors?",
    "Questions copy": "Who is the judge of the qualifications of Tulsa's City Councilors?",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's City Council is the judge of the qualifications of its members. In doing so, it has \"the power to subpoena witnesses and require the production of records. The decisions of the Council in such cases shall be subject to review by appropriate actions in courts of competent jurisdiction which shall be commenced within ten (10) days after a final decision by the Council\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(6.1) - Judge of Qualifications"
  },
  {
    "id": "recSxXDgwTIEu9ZI0",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/23/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, city council, meetings",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recOZcthnnGwf2z2t"
    ],
    "Question": "How many of Tulsa's City Councilors must be present to constitute a quorum for a meeting? ",
    "Questions copy": "How many of Tulsa's City Councilors must be present to constitute a quorum for a meeting? ",
    "Answer": "A majority of the entire membership of Tulsa's City Council must be present to constitute a quorum for City Council meetings. Further, \"less than a majority may continue a meeting to a specific date and time. The affirmative vote of a majority of the entire membership of the Council shall be necessary to adopt an ordinance or resolution\". Finally, actions of the Council are effective following an affirmative vote of a qurom.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(6.2) - Quorum and voting"
  },
  {
    "id": "recY0lFILWjyxu92N",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/23/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, city council, ordinances",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "reclF9NgSrsJW92dI"
    ],
    "Question": "When do ordinances go into effect?",
    "Questions copy": "When do ordinances go into effect?",
    "Answer": "Upon an affirmative vote of a majority of a qurom of Tulsa's City Council. Further, \"a majority of the entire membership of the Council shall constitute a quorom for a meeting of the Council\". However, as revealed in Section 9 of the City Charter, \"Ordinances adopting budgets, making appropriations, pertaining to local improvements and assessments, and any ordinance or resolution adopted as an emergency measure shall take effect at the time stated therein. All other ordinances and resolutions shall take effect at the time stated therein, but not less than thirty (30) days from the date of first publication. Ordinances adopted by vote of the electors shall take effect at the time stated therein or, if no time be stated, thirty (30) days after the election. An ordinance or resolution adopted as an emergency measure to provide for the immediate preservation of the public peace, health, welfare, or safety shall describe the emergency in a separate section. The vote of at least two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to adopt any ordinance or resolution as an emergency measure\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(6.2) - Quorum and voting"
  },
  {
    "id": "recmP8tQuyN5MtU1k",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/23/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, city council, ordinances, voting, zoning, protests, property owners, meetings, public hearings",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recDctKj7bLVOerpI"
    ],
    "Question": "How can Tulsans block a zoning change?",
    "Questions copy": "How can Tulsans block a zoning change?",
    "Answer": "By convincing the property owners impacted by the zoning change to file a protest against the zoning change, Tulsans can raise the bar for the number of votes required for the zoning ordinance to go into effect - instead requiring the City Council to have three-fourths (3/4) of the entire membership of the Council to enact the zoning change. Such protests must meet two requirements. First, protests must be filed at least three (3) days prior to the hearing of the zoning change by City Council. Second, protests must be supported by either (a) owners of at least 20% of the area of the lots included in the proposed change or (b) owners of at least 50% of the area of the lots within a 300 foot radius of the exterior boundary of the territory included in the proposed change.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(6.3) - Voting on zoning changes involving protests"
  },
  {
    "id": "recHzCmT1NJB6v7B8",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/23/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, spending, budgets, city council, mayor, mayor-council relations",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recEkG7YSqnpQ9l4I"
    ],
    "Question": "What must occur prior to Tulsa City Council's expenditure of general funds?",
    "Questions copy": "What must occur prior to Tulsa City Council's expenditure of general funds?",
    "Answer": "\"The Mayor shall submit to the Council a budget for the expenditure of such funds or amendments to previously adopted budgets. The Council shall adopt budgets or amendments and make appropriations by ordinance, provided, that no revenue derived from the 2017 Public Safety Sales Tax, as set forth in detail in Title 43-I Tulsa Revised Ordinances, shall ever be budgeted, spent or used for any purpose other than public safety as described therein\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.1) - Budgets"
  },
  {
    "id": "recOtmAvGMoCcVV9J",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/23/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, spending, budgets, city council, mayor, mayor-council relations",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "reczCm4avq1CSqz4I"
    ],
    "Question": "What must occur prior to Tulsa City Council's expenditure of funds from the sale or issuance of an obligation of the city, or from any other source?",
    "Questions copy": "\"What must occur prior to Tulsa City Council's expenditure of funds from the sale or issuance of an obligation of the city, or from any other source?\"",
    "Answer": "\"The Mayor shall submit to the Council a budget for the expenditure of such funds or amendments to previously adopted budgets. The Council shall adopt budgets or amendments and make appropriations by ordinance, provided, that no revenue derived from the 2017 Public Safety Sales Tax, as set forth in detail in Title 43-I Tulsa Revised Ordinances, shall ever be budgeted, spent or used for any purpose other than public safety as described therein\". The special treatement of the 2017 Public Safety Sales Tax was the result of an amendment supported by 6,602 Tulsans. 3,640 Tulsans voted against the amendment.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.1) - Budgets"
  },
  {
    "id": "recpPbQeeDgWdhDYK",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/23/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, spending, budgets, city council, mayor, mayor-council relations, meetings, public hearings",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recze7ORmMp2clvxf"
    ],
    "Question": "What public hearings must City Council hold upon receipt of budgets from the Mayor?",
    "Questions copy": "What public hearings must City Council hold upon receipt of budgets from the Mayor?",
    "Answer": "At least one public hearing, during which \"any citizen of the city shall be given an opportunity to be heard on the budgets or any item or program reccommended therein. After public hearing, the Council may adopt a budget or amendments. The Council may add, delete, increase, or decrease programs or amounts, except expenditures required by law\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.2) - Action on Budgets"
  },
  {
    "id": "recGWOXkVNbwDlXAv",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/23/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, spending, budgets, city council, mayor, mayor-council relations,",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recnfegL8rt7wX3Vk"
    ],
    "Question": "How can Tulsa's City Council alter budgets submitted by the Mayor?",
    "Questions copy": "How can Tulsa's City Council alter budgets submitted by the Mayor?",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's City Council \"may add, delete, increase, or decrease programs or amounts, except expenditures required by law\" with respect to the budgets recieved from the Mayor.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.2) - Action on Budgets"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec3f5OzhvG9UELpF",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/23/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authority, spending, budgets, city council, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recmmomqhk0MJTDG4"
    ],
    "Question": "Can Tulsa's City Council establish additional procedures for the preparation, adoption, and amendment of budgets?, for the transfer of appropriations, and for supplemental and emergency appropriations which are not in conflict with the provisions of this amended Charter or with the laws of ",
    "Questions copy": "\"Can Tulsa's City Council establish additional procedures for the preparation, adoption, and amendment of budgets?, for the transfer of appropriations, and for supplemental and emergency appropriations which are not in conflict with the provisions of this amended Charter or with the laws of \"",
    "Answer": "Yes. \"The Council may establish by ordinance additional procedures for the preparation, adoption, and amendment of budgets, for the transfer of appropriations, and for supplemental and emergency appropriations which are not in conflict with the provisions of this amended Charter or with the laws of Oklahoma\"",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.3) - Additional procedures"
  },
  {
    "id": "recwMgKY7yab2Eh2i",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/23/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, economics, budgets, general fund budget, economic stabilization reserve",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recYGrUyBXjHPoqep"
    ],
    "Question": "What is the purpose of Tulsa's Economic Stabilization Reserve?",
    "Questions copy": "What is the purpose of Tulsa's Economic Stabilization Reserve?",
    "Answer": "The Economic Stabilization Reserve assists to limit \"the amount of reduction required in the general fund budget during times of declining revenues\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.4) - Economic stabilization reserve created"
  },
  {
    "id": "recBQyKyvFr03LEjH",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/23/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, economics, budgets, general fund budget, city treasurer, budgets, economic stabilization reserve, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recaQLFDJyoC7IIgF"
    ],
    "Question": "Where are revenues in excess of the projected General Fund to be allocated?",
    "Questions copy": "Where are revenues in excess of the projected General Fund to be allocated?",
    "Answer": "\"If the City Treasurer projects that total General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year will exceed the total General Fund revenues for the current budget year by more than four percent (4%), the budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by the City Council shall allocate the excess General Fund revenues as follows:\n\nA. Fifty percent (50%) of the excess General Fund revenues to the Economic Stabilization Reserve;\n\nB. Twenty-five percent (25%) of the excess General Fund revenues may be allocated in whole or in part to capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve; and,\n\nC. Twenty-five percent (25%) of the excess General Fund revenues may be allocated for general use consistent with lawful municipal purposes.\n\nThe Mayor and the City Council may, at any time, authorize any other available monies to be added to the Economic Stabilization Reserve; however, total monies in the Economic Stabilization Reserve shall not exceed thirty percent (30%) of actual total General Fund revenues\". \"The budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by the City Council shall allocate excess revenues that would otherwise be allocated to the Economic Stabilization Reserve above the thirty percent (30%) cap instead to capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve\". This must be conducted in accordance with the provisions of section B. However, for any of the aformentioned to go into effect, projected revenues must initially exceed $250,000, per section 7.10 of the City Charter.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.5) - Allocations to the economic stabilization reserve."
  },
  {
    "id": "recYTqVCkED3OBSa2",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/24/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, economics, budgets, general fund budget, budgets, economic stabilization reserve, capital, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recq94IbAD8EnVIHN"
    ],
    "Question": "In what ways are the Mayor and Tulsa's City Council limited in adding money to the Economic Stabilization Reserve?",
    "Questions copy": "In what ways are the Mayor and Tulsa's City Council limited in adding money to the Economic Stabilization Reserve?",
    "Answer": "While the Mayor and Tulsa's City Council may, at any point in time, authorize any available funds to be added to the Economic Stabilization Reserve, the total in the Economic Stabilization Reserve shall not exceed 30% of actual total General Fund revenues. When this 30% cap is met, the budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by the City Council shall allocate excess revenues that would otherwise be allocated to the Economic Stabilization to capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve. However, such capital, other one-time expenditures, and the operating reserve must not exceed 25% of the excess General Fund revenues. Finally, all of the aformentioned allocations are only required where projected revenues initially exceed $250,000, per Sectiomn 7.10 in the City Charter.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.5) - Allocations to the economic stabilization reserve."
  },
  {
    "id": "reccqMX2LrXhNalmZ",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/24/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, economics, budgets, general fund budget, budgets, capital, information systems, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recFLeOGgaR9kA2Sd"
    ],
    "Question": "For what may the Mayor and Tulsa's City Council appropriate funds allocated to capital or other one-time expenditures for?",
    "Questions copy": "For what may the Mayor and Tulsa's City Council appropriate funds allocated to capital or other one-time expenditures for?",
    "Answer": "The Mayor and Tulsa's City Council \"may, at any time, appropriate monies from the capital and/or other one-time expenditures allocation for capital projects or for expenditures such as, but not limited to, acquisition of equipment or information systems\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.6) - Use of monies allocated to capital or other one-time expenditures"
  },
  {
    "id": "recVTjmtC31O570Jx",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/24/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, economics, budgets, general fund budget, budgets, capital, information systems, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recdgthAZOpFRVa69"
    ],
    "Question": "Can capital funds be used to by the Mayor and Tulsa's City Council to purchase information systems?",
    "Questions copy": "Can capital funds be used to by the Mayor and Tulsa's City Council to purchase information systems?",
    "Answer": "Yes. The Mayor and Tulsa's City Council \"may, at any time, appropriate monies from the capital and/or other one-time expenditures allocation for capital projects or for expenditures such as, but not limited to, acquisition of equipment or information systems\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.6) - Use of monies allocated to capital or other one-time expenditures"
  },
  {
    "id": "recj7BbeCn5BW02C5",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/24/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, economics, budgets, general fund budget, budgets, capital, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recns6Po19HmY0oyc"
    ],
    "Question": "For what may the Mayor and City Council use funds allocated to general purpose?",
    "Questions copy": "For what may the Mayor and City Council use funds allocated to general purpose?",
    "Answer": "\"The Mayor and the City Council may, at any time, appropriate monies from the general purpose allocation for any lawful municipal purpose\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.7) - Use of monies allocated for general purposes"
  },
  {
    "id": "recHrxqOnENuB36sb",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Suggestion": "Connect with some page on \"What to do when the City doesn't raise enough money\" OR call it \"What options are available to the City of Tulsa to resolve budget concerns when budget projections are low?\"",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budgets, city treasurer, economic stabilization reserve",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recOmyIu0QxBEQqgV"
    ],
    "Question": "Under what conditions may the budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by Tulsa's City Council appropriate up to 50% of the current balance in the Economic Stabilization Reserve for any lawful municipal purpose?",
    "Questions copy": "Under what conditions may the budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by Tulsa's City Council appropriate up to 50% of the current balance in the Economic Stabilization Reserve for any lawful municipal purpose?",
    "Answer": "\"If the City Treasurer projects that total General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year will either (a) be less than the current budget year's total General Fund revenues, or (b) be less than the highest of any other previous year's total General Fund revenues, the budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by the Council may appropriate up to fifty percent (50%) of the current balance in the Economic Stabilization Reserve, but no more than the shortfall in total General Fund revenues as determined above, to be used for any lawful municipal purpose in the upcoming budget year. For purposes of calculating any shortfall:\n\nA. If the trigger for withdrawals from the reserve was not met in the current budget year, the City Treasurer shall calculate the shortfall for the upcoming budget year by subtracting the total projected General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year from the total projected General Fund revenues for the current budget year.\n\nB. If the trigger for withdrawals from the Economic Stabilization Reserve was met in the current budget year, the shortfall shall be calculated by subtracting the total projected General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year from the highest of any previous year's total General Fund revenues\". As outlined in Section 7.9 of the City Charter, the City may withdrawl the percentage of negative growth in the Consumer Price Index if the City Treasurer projects that the Consumer Price Index for the upcoming budget year will be less than the index for the current budget year.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.8) - Withdrawals from the economic stabilization reserve."
  },
  {
    "id": "rec7OXZdV7bSm9eCD",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budgets, economic stabilization reserve, capital, operating reserve, one-time expenditures",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recg0ixkhBeUqQVej"
    ],
    "Question": "Under what conditions is the City of Tulsa not required to allocate any anticipated excess revenues as outlined in the allocations to the Economic Stabilization Reserve?",
    "Questions copy": "Under what conditions is the City of Tulsa not required to allocate any anticipated excess revenues as outlined in the allocations to the Economic Stabilization Reserve?",
    "Answer": "The City of Tulsa is not required to allocate any anticiapted excess revenues for the upcoming budget year as outlined in the regulations concerning allocation to the Economic Stabilization Reserve if the City both (1) made appropriations from the Economic Stabilization Reserve in the current budget year and in the immediately preceding budget year pursuent to regulations for withdrawls from the Economic Stabilization Reserve.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.9) - Adjustments to allocations to the economic stabilization reserve, capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve."
  },
  {
    "id": "recCnTQJqAYaNopVz",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budgets, economic stabilization reserve, capital, operating reserve, one-time expenditures, consumer price index, city treasurer",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recXs1flaptEVIw6G"
    ],
    "Question": "Where adjustments to the Economic Stabilization Reserve, Capital, Other One-Time Expenditures, or Operating Reserve are concerned, what product is the City Treasurer required to rely on when making projections for the Consumer Price Index?",
    "Questions copy": "\"Where adjustments to the Economic Stabilization Reserve, Capital, Other One-Time Expenditures, or Operating Reserve are concerned, what product is the City Treasurer required to rely on when making projections for the Consumer Price Index?\"",
    "Answer": "The All Items Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers (CPI-U) - or its succesor as determined by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, a bureau of the U.S. Department of Labor.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.9) - Adjustments to allocations to the economic stabilization reserve, capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve."
  },
  {
    "id": "recQ2V7AshgwSh9MH",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budgets, economic stabilization reserve, capital, operating reserve, one-time expenditures, consumer price index, city treasurer",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recfjeXv4Ol0a6SKJ"
    ],
    "Question": "Under what conditions are allocations to the Economic Stabilization Reserve by the City of Tulsa triggered by a Consumer Price Index growth rate percentage (plus 2%) rather than the City Treasurer's projections that the total General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year will exceed the total General Fund revenues for the current budget year by more than 4%?",
    "Questions copy": "Under what conditions are allocations to the Economic Stabilization Reserve by the City of Tulsa triggered by a Consumer Price Index growth rate percentage (plus 2%) rather than the City Treasurer's projections that the total General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year will exceed the total General Fund revenues for the current budget year by more than 4%?",
    "Answer": "When the City Treasurer projects that the Consumer Price Index for the upcoming budget year will exceed the index for the current budget year by more than five percent (5%). When this happens, the following allocations are triggered: \nA. Fifty percent (50%) of the excess General Fund revenues to the Economic Stabilization Reserve;\n\nB. Twenty-five percent (25%) of the excess General Fund revenues may be allocated in whole or in part to capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve; and,\n\nC. Twenty-five percent (25%) of the excess General Fund revenues may be allocated for general use consistent with lawful municipal purposes.\n\nThe Mayor and the City Council may, at any time, authorize any other available monies to be added to the Economic Stabilization Reserve; however, total monies in the Economic Stabilization Reserve shall not exceed thirty percent (30%) of actual total General Fund revenues\". \"The budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by the City Council shall allocate excess revenues that would otherwise be allocated to the Economic Stabilization Reserve above the thirty percent (30%) cap instead to capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve\". This must be conducted in accordance with the provisions of section B.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.9) - Adjustments to allocations to the economic stabilization reserve, capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve."
  },
  {
    "id": "reccL19j538GHHPPo",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budgets, economic stabilization reserve, capital, operating reserve, one-time expenditures, consumer price index",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "rec1ytzgav73eUXOD"
    ],
    "Question": "Are revenue changes to the General Fund caused by actions made by Tulsa's City Council or voters counted as part of triggers for allocations to or withdrawls from the Economic Stabilization Reserve in the year in which the revenue change is made?",
    "Questions copy": "Are revenue changes to the General Fund caused by actions made by Tulsa's City Council or voters counted as part of triggers for allocations to or withdrawls from the Economic Stabilization Reserve in the year in which the revenue change is made?",
    "Answer": "Definitely not. If the City Council or the voters take any action that changes the amount of total General Fund revenues in any material manner, including but not limited to reducing a tax or imposing a new fee, the revenue changes caused by that action shall not be counted as part of the trigger for allocations to the Economic Stabilization Reserve during the year or years in which the action is first implemented.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.9) - Adjustments to allocations to the economic stabilization reserve, capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve."
  },
  {
    "id": "recm1OZlsVsBlNNkh",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budgets, economic stabilization reserve, capital, operating reserve, one-time expenditures, consumer price index",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "rec8FmPSfA9S4pcre"
    ],
    "Question": "Who is responsible for rebalancing the allocations to or withdrawls from the Economic Stabilization Reserve, Capital, Other One-Time Expenditures, or Operating Reserve with actual revenue results (as state in the City of Tulsa's independent annual audit) in conjunection with the annual year-end of close of the budget?",
    "Questions copy": "\"Who is responsible for rebalancing the allocations to or withdrawls from the Economic Stabilization Reserve, Capital, Other One-Time Expenditures, or Operating Reserve with actual revenue results (as state in the City of Tulsa's independent annual audit) in conjunection with the annual year-end of close of the budget?\"",
    "Answer": "The City Treasurer.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(7.9) - Adjustments to allocations to the economic stabilization reserve, capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve."
  },
  {
    "id": "rec5ZiLFEq0F5HUUF",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recpZT3q1xsg1ueCk"
    ],
    "Question": "In what form must ordinances and resolutions be introduced in Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Questions copy": "In what form must ordinances and resolutions be introduced in Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Answer": "In written or printed form.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "recFDXly6FTOQVZpH",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "rec1VN6atVxRUlmnT"
    ],
    "Question": "Which ordinances must be confined to one subject?",
    "Questions copy": "Which ordinances must be confined to one subject?",
    "Answer": "\"All ordinances or resolutions, except those adopting budgets, making appropriations, or adopting a code of ordinances, shall be confined to one subject, which shall be clearly expressed in the title\"",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "reclKGzEXFqBT0RC6",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recfNuLpuMTv1mcF2"
    ],
    "Question": "Must ordinances be clearly expressed in the title of the ordinance?",
    "Questions copy": "Must ordinances be clearly expressed in the title of the ordinance?",
    "Answer": "Yes. \"All ordinances or resolutions, except those adopting budgets, making appropriations, or adopting a code of ordinances, shall be confined to one subject, which shall be clearly expressed in the title\"",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "recslOOw5TIQK8nOU",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, budgets",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "reckKaWp4EkNwUJDr"
    ],
    "Question": "Can ordinances that involve adopting budgets or making appropriations involve anything else?",
    "Questions copy": "Can ordinances that involve adopting budgets or making appropriations involve anything else?",
    "Answer": "No. \"Ordinances adopting budgets and making appropriations shall be confined to budgets and appropriations\"",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "reccYueoJds3WA3WE",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recGYfeKeg1n83sq4"
    ],
    "Question": "How many meetings must an ordinance be on Tulsa's City Council agenda before it can be adopted?",
    "Questions copy": "How many meetings must an ordinance be on Tulsa's City Council agenda before it can be adopted?",
    "Answer": "Two. However, Tulsa's City Council can waive this requirement with a vote of two thirds of the entire membership of the Council.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "recWfxeXOGk90EVtM",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recJ0UrR0XFC2qPfG"
    ],
    "Question": "Must a copy of each proposed ordinance shall be furnished to each Councilor or left at the usual place of residence of each Councilor prior to final consideration?",
    "Questions copy": "Must a copy of each proposed ordinance shall be furnished to each Councilor or left at the usual place of residence of each Councilor prior to final consideration?",
    "Answer": "Yes.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "reco0DBfcy738b3oR",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "rec1ymuI0SzKyUk6F"
    ],
    "Question": "Must a vote of each Councilor shall be taken upon all matters before the Council and entered in the journal of the proceedings of the Council?",
    "Questions copy": "Must a vote of each Councilor shall be taken upon all matters before the Council and entered in the journal of the proceedings of the Council?",
    "Answer": "Yes.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "recxpQC8bGuTwTUlR",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "reckwtnIsWpDL1fgX"
    ],
    "Question": "What is the enacting clause for all of the City of Tulsa's ordinances?",
    "Questions copy": "What is the enacting clause for all of the City of Tulsa's ordinances?",
    "Answer": "\"Be it Ordained by the City of Tulsa\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(8) - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "reclVv1QZFmXmvuli",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, vetos",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recJzAooe967Ct1xJ"
    ],
    "Question": "Once the Mayor recieves ordinances voted in by the City of Tulsa, how long does the Mayor have to either approve or veto the ordinance?",
    "Questions copy": "\"Once the Mayor recieves ordinances voted in by the City of Tulsa, how long does the Mayor have to either approve or veto the ordinance?\"",
    "Answer": "15 days. \"Within fifteen (15) working days following such delivery, the Mayor shall either approve or veto the ordinance or resolution. If vetoed, the ordinance or resolution shall be returned to the Council with a written statement of the objections of the Mayor. If neither approved nor vetoed by the Mayor in the time specified, the ordinance or resolution shall take effect as though approved by the Mayor. A veto by the Mayor shall suspend further action of the Council upon the ordinance or resolution for a period of seven (7) days, after which the Council may override the veto by a vote of two-thirds (⅔) of its entire membership, and the ordinance or resolution shall take effect as though approved by the Mayor. If the veto of the Mayor is sustained, the subject of the ordinance or resolution, except ordinances adopting budgets or making appropriations, shall not be further considered by the Council for a period of ninety (90) days; provided, that the Council by a vote of two-thirds (⅔) of its entire membership may waive the ninety (90) day period\"",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(9) - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "recRijJMbqRqPNl3v",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, vetos",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recZHpStuZfLdBWcV"
    ],
    "Question": "How many votes are needed in Tulsa's City Council to overturn a Mayor's veto of an ordinance?",
    "Questions copy": "How many votes are needed in Tulsa's City Council to overturn a Mayor's veto of an ordinance?",
    "Answer": "2/3rds of the entire membership of Tulsa's City Council are required to overturn a Mayor's veto. Once this vote takes place, the ordinance goes into effect as if supported by the Mayor.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(9) - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "recgyVa2YEXEsUsSU",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, vetos",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recaeurItpV3zCf38"
    ],
    "Question": "How long does Tulsa's City Council have to wait after the Mayor vetos an ordinance before the Council can vote to overturn the veto?",
    "Questions copy": "How long does Tulsa's City Council have to wait after the Mayor vetos an ordinance before the Council can vote to overturn the veto?",
    "Answer": "Seven days, ...\"after which the Council may override the veto by a vote of two-thirds (⅔) of its entire membership, and the ordinance or resolution shall take effect as though approved by the Mayor\"",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(9) - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "recAmw5u9QGUZhH8E",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, vetos",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recI4GTiCISyRF6VD"
    ],
    "Question": "If Tulsa's City Council fails to overturn the Mayor's veto on a given ordinance, how long must the Council wait before the ordinance can be reconsidered?",
    "Questions copy": "\"If Tulsa's City Council fails to overturn the Mayor's veto on a given ordinance, how long must the Council wait before the ordinance can be reconsidered?\"",
    "Answer": "90 days. \"f the veto of the Mayor is sustained, the subject of the ordinance or resolution, except ordinances adopting budgets or making appropriations, shall not be further considered by the Council for a period of ninety (90) days; provided, that the Council by a vote of two-thirds (⅔) of its entire membership may waive the ninety (90) day period\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(9) - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "recH0DMjb0xYKi2Xp",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, vetos, mayor",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recEQZOozsoC3Cj7W"
    ],
    "Question": "What can Tulsa's Mayor veto?",
    "Questions copy": "What can Tulsa's Mayor veto?",
    "Answer": "The Mayor may veto or even reduce any item of ordinances that adopt budgets or make appropriations, unless otherwise provided in the City Charter.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(9) - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "recL7ZO9ltM8ztOxo",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, emergency measures",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recuDxASxgBKeY728"
    ],
    "Question": "How many votes are needed in Tulsa's City Council to adopt an ordinance as an emergency measure? ",
    "Questions copy": "How many votes are needed in Tulsa's City Council to adopt an ordinance as an emergency measure? ",
    "Answer": "2/3rds of the entire membership of the Council. \"Further,  An ordinance or resolution adopted as an emergency measure to provide for the immediate preservation of the public peace, health, welfare, or safety shall describe the emergency in a separate section\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(10) - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "recBmy0nIGPxVmI1B",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, city clerk",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recOqf3VDixaaq1es"
    ],
    "Question": "Who's responsibility is it to attest to and record ordinances and resolutions adopted by Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Questions copy": "Who's responsibility is it to attest to and record ordinances and resolutions adopted by Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Answer": "The City Clerk.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(11) - Recording and publication of ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "recDipAILDoBWzGwb",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, city clerk, public relations",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recfDl46HX4vYLsU2"
    ],
    "Question": "How long does the City of Tulsa have after an ordinance is adopted to be published in a newspaper of general circulation?",
    "Questions copy": "How long does the City of Tulsa have after an ordinance is adopted to be published in a newspaper of general circulation?",
    "Answer": "10 days. \"Ordinances and resolutions shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation within the city within ten (10) days after approval. Codifications of ordinances and codes of law adopted by reference need not be published in full unless otherwise provided by the Council\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(11) - Recording and publication of ordinances and resolutions."
  },
  {
    "id": "rec5Jd51Qy5nHqHDR",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, city clerk, titles, emergency measures, code of ordinances",
    "Questions": [
      "recvpitaSSSVzoI73"
    ],
    "Question": "What is permitted to be omitted from the Code of Ordinances?",
    "Questions copy": "What is permitted to be omitted from the Code of Ordinances?",
    "Answer": "\"Titles, enacting clauses, emergency sections, and temporary and special ordinances may be omitted from the code. Ordinances and parts of ordinances which are to be repealed by the adoption of a revised code may be omitted. A revised code may contain new matter\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(12) - Codification of Ordinances"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec2QN5rKbAzbptzA",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, city clerk, titles, emergency measures, code of ordinances",
    "Questions": [
      "reclq0b7jcBkQT7Ay"
    ],
    "Question": "Who is responsible for keeping copies of the Code of Ordinances to sell to the public?",
    "Questions copy": "Who is responsible for keeping copies of the Code of Ordinances to sell to the public?",
    "Answer": "The City Clerk.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(12) - Codification of Ordinances"
  },
  {
    "id": "recxkLXUyyVSdgcDn",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, titles, emergency measures, code of ordinances",
    "Questions": [
      "recNdX8y3jgzE5uBD"
    ],
    "Question": "Who is responsible for revising and maintaining the Code of Ordinances?",
    "Questions copy": "Who is responsible for revising and maintaining the Code of Ordinances?",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's City Council",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(12) - Codification of Ordinances"
  },
  {
    "id": "recUZOoV0IQjaCg7p",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, punishments, imprisonment",
    "Questions": [
      "recYJpTO43OKiz8gD"
    ],
    "Question": "May Tulsa's City Council prescribe imprisonment as a punishment for the violation of ordinances?",
    "Questions copy": "May Tulsa's City Council prescribe imprisonment as a punishment for the violation of ordinances?",
    "Answer": "Yes. \"The Council may, subject to the limitations of the Constitution and the laws of Oklahoma, prescribe penalties for the violation of ordinances, including fines and imprisonment\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(13) - Penalties for violation of ordinances."
  },
  {
    "id": "rec7Xy1dNuTxZpQGI",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, punishments, fines",
    "Questions": [
      "recWNHr3FIOHpEz9f"
    ],
    "Question": "May Tulsa's City Council prescribe fines as a punishment for the violation of ordinances?",
    "Questions copy": "May Tulsa's City Council prescribe fines as a punishment for the violation of ordinances?",
    "Answer": "Yes. \"The Council may, subject to the limitations of the Constitution and the laws of Oklahoma, prescribe penalties for the violation of ordinances, including fines and imprisonment\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(13) - Penalties for violation of ordinances."
  },
  {
    "id": "recz84mofMhULcSvO",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, punishments",
    "Questions": [
      "recLWuW1Pd9GAC7So"
    ],
    "Question": "May Tulsa's City Council prescribe penalites as a punishment for the violation of ordinances?",
    "Questions copy": "May Tulsa's City Council prescribe penalites as a punishment for the violation of ordinances?",
    "Answer": "Yes. \"The Council may, subject to the limitations of the Constitution and the laws of Oklahoma, prescribe penalties for the violation of ordinances, including fines and imprisonment\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(13) - Penalties for violation of ordinances."
  },
  {
    "id": "recbdEfc9lxTdscC5",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, city charter",
    "Questions": [
      "recs7sGDHP8jrTAkC"
    ],
    "Question": "How must Tulsa's City Council provide for review of the amended City Charter?",
    "Questions copy": "How must Tulsa's City Council provide for review of the amended City Charter?",
    "Answer": "By ordinance. \"The Council shall provide by ordinance for the periodic review of this amended Charter and shall submit to the qualified electors of the city amendments necessary to provide for representative, efficient, and economical administration of city government\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(14) - Charter Review."
  },
  {
    "id": "rec18F7cSBk7ba16Z",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, city council, governance, state of oklahoma, authority, sovereignty",
    "Questions": [
      "recJWCqMOuLqKvqWZ"
    ],
    "Question": "Are the legislative powers of Tulsa's City Council subordinate and subject to the rights of initiative and referendum reserved to the people by the Constitution of Oklahoma?",
    "Questions copy": "Are the legislative powers of Tulsa's City Council subordinate and subject to the rights of initiative and referendum reserved to the people by the Constitution of Oklahoma?",
    "Answer": "Yes. \"All legislative powers vested by this amended Charter in the Council are subordinate and subject to the rights of initiative and referendum reserved to the people by the Constitution of Oklahoma\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(15) - Initiative and Referendum"
  },
  {
    "id": "recD9Fjqa0ekN0QN6",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/27/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, administrative review",
    "Questions": [
      "rec1ds5meCdh84sx3"
    ],
    "Question": "By what means does Tulsa's City Council review administrative actions?",
    "Questions copy": "By what means does Tulsa's City Council review administrative actions?",
    "Answer": "By ordinance. \"The Council shall provide by ordinance for the grant, issuance, modification, amendment, or revocation of orders, licenses, permits, certificates, and approvals by the divisions, departments, and agencies of the city. Except when otherwise provided by the laws of Oklahoma, the grant, issuance, modification, amendment, or revocation of orders, licenses, permits, certificates, and approvals shall be subject to review by the Council, upon petition by an aggrieved person, in accord with procedures which the Council shall establish by ordinance. The Council may not abrogate any right of review by a court of competent jurisdiction\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(16) - Review of Administrative Actions"
  },
  {
    "id": "rech7dFRMm3t2hUBB",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/28/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, administrative review",
    "Questions": [
      "rec3Jn0DlrFfUHiOy"
    ],
    "Question": "Can Tulsa's City Council abrogate any right of review by a court of competent jurisdiction with respect to administrative review?",
    "Questions copy": "Can Tulsa's City Council abrogate any right of review by a court of competent jurisdiction with respect to administrative review?",
    "Answer": "No. \"The Council may not abrogate any right of review by a court of competent jurisdiction\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(16) - Review of Administrative Actions"
  },
  {
    "id": "recQTLkxwWu1Q3wSX",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/28/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, hearings, public comment",
    "Questions": [
      "recGKUTEcX6hXBJUv"
    ],
    "Question": "Concerning investigations and hearings, must City Council hear complaints made by citizens concerning the administration of city government?",
    "Questions copy": "\"Concerning investigations and hearings, must City Council hear complaints made by citizens concerning the administration of city government?\"",
    "Answer": "Yes. \"The Council shall hear complaints made by citizens concerning the administration of the city government\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(17) - Investigations and Hearings"
  },
  {
    "id": "recEHXwNFGAN0jFpe",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/28/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, hearings",
    "Questions": [
      "rec2t2g8O4cKwQnSa"
    ],
    "Question": "May Tulsa's City Council investigate the conduct of the city government?",
    "Questions copy": "May Tulsa's City Council investigate the conduct of the city government?",
    "Answer": "Yes. \"The Council may investigate the conduct of the city government and may make appraisals, comments, and recommendations to the Mayor on the efficiency, economy, and effectiveness of administrative practices, methods, systems, and controls\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(17) - Investigations and Hearings"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec2iciURmDP9LOwQ",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/28/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, hearings, subpoenas, evidence",
    "Questions": [
      "rec8MDgogQxyQd72T"
    ],
    "Question": "May Tulsa's City Council subpoena witnesses as necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?",
    "Questions copy": "May Tulsa's City Council subpoena witnesses as necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?",
    "Answer": "Yes. \"The Council may subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, and compel testimony, the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(17) - Investigations and Hearings"
  },
  {
    "id": "recWMdfDSgX8XKUzo",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/28/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, hearings, oaths, evidence",
    "Questions": [
      "recJTBtPNNCOkfttt"
    ],
    "Question": "May Tulsa's City Council administer oaths as necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?",
    "Questions copy": "May Tulsa's City Council administer oaths as necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?",
    "Answer": "Yes. \"The Council may subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, and compel testimony, the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(17) - Investigations and Hearings"
  },
  {
    "id": "recD7uvmCs85gzSLs",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/28/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, hearings, evidence, testimony",
    "Questions": [
      "recfT87Zh1Ku5lapV"
    ],
    "Question": "May Tulsa's City Council compel testimony as necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?",
    "Questions copy": "May Tulsa's City Council compel testimony as necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?",
    "Answer": "Yes. \"The Council may subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, and compel testimony, the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(17) - Investigations and Hearings"
  },
  {
    "id": "recG5qLjzns8yMEse",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/28/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, hearings, evidence",
    "Questions": [
      "recngl4yrD4mYhHOu"
    ],
    "Question": "May Tulsa's City Council compel the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?",
    "Questions copy": "\"May Tulsa's City Council compel the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?\"",
    "Answer": "Yes. \"The Council may subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, and compel testimony, the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(17) - Investigations and Hearings"
  },
  {
    "id": "recYWKTFnXTvpTCAo",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/28/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, hearings, ordinances",
    "Questions": [
      "recP19FQxiRhGq9jq"
    ],
    "Question": "How may Tulsa's City Council provide the penalties for the contempt by any person who refuses to obey a Council order or subpoena?",
    "Questions copy": "How may Tulsa's City Council provide the penalties for the contempt by any person who refuses to obey a Council order or subpoena?",
    "Answer": "By ordinance. \"The Council shall provide by ordinance the penalties for the contempt by any person who refuses to obey a Council order or subpoena\"",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(17) - Investigations and Hearings"
  },
  {
    "id": "recBPY7GOmfmJD6OT",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/28/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, investigations, subpoenas, evidence, mayor",
    "Questions": [
      "recT2hPeqmUfQsHqy"
    ],
    "Question": "Who designates the police officers to serve orders and subpoenas issued by Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Questions copy": "Who designates the police officers to serve orders and subpoenas issued by Tulsa's City Council?",
    "Answer": "\"The Mayor shall designate police officers to serve orders and subpoenas issued by the Council\"",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(17) - Investigations and Hearings"
  },
  {
    "id": "recbsGXH3aOUdh1ts",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/28/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, authority, mayor",
    "Questions": [
      "recK3kTvH7TyMdYnQ"
    ],
    "Question": "May Tulsa's City Council delegate to the Mayor the authority to make rules, regulations, and orders necessary and proper to implement and administer ordinances?",
    "Questions copy": "\"May Tulsa's City Council delegate to the Mayor the authority to make rules, regulations, and orders necessary and proper to implement and administer ordinances?\"",
    "Answer": "Yes. \"The Council may delegate to the Mayor the authority to make rules, regulations, and orders necessary and proper to implement and administer ordinances\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(18) - Delegation of authority to make rules"
  },
  {
    "id": "recw7DYpf4ikRLZHM",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "7/28/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, ordinances, resolutions, city council, governance, authority, mayor, administration, appointments, removals",
    "Questions": [
      "reczUZZWw3qeYAUYf"
    ],
    "Question": "Barring investigations and hearings, through what avenues is it legal for Tulsa's City Council or individual councilors to communicate on matters of city business with the executive and administrative service?",
    "Questions copy": "\"Barring investigations and hearings, through what avenues is it legal for Tulsa's City Council or individual councilors to communicate on matters of city business with the executive and administrative service?\"",
    "Answer": "\"...soley through the Mayor, the heads of each division and department of the City, as well as such other persons as the Mayor shall delegate\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(19) - Interference with appointments or removals"
  },
  {
    "id": "recrlApGSQpymdPlv",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/9/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, city council, governance, authority, mayor, administration, Appointments, removals",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recUOJwJNzbczRXpT"
    ],
    "Question": "Can City Councilors give orders to the Mayor's subordinates?",
    "Questions copy": "Can City Councilors give orders to the Mayor's subordinates?",
    "Answer": "Barring the City Clerk, and the City Attorney, no. \"The Council and Councilors shall not give orders to any subordinate of the Mayor, either publicly or privately; provided, the prohibitions of this sentence shall not apply to the City Clerk and the City Attorney. Violation of this Section by any Councilor shall constitute willful maladministration and be sufficient grounds for removal from office as provided by the laws of Oklahoma\". The answer to this question is sourced from documentation concerning interference with appointments or removals.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(19) - Interference with appointments or removals"
  },
  {
    "id": "recGQbFFz9L2lMD2q",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/9/2022",
    "Article": 2,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, city council, mayor, spending, lawsuits, claims, law",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recQzBzYvxnoI3suZ"
    ],
    "Question": "How much money does a claim have to involve before the Mayor's approval and majority vote of the City Council is required?",
    "Questions copy": "How much money does a claim have to involve before the Mayor's approval and majority vote of the City Council is required?",
    "Answer": "$1 million. \"Where a claim is asserted against the City of Tulsa seeking to recover $1 million or more, prior to any settlement of such claim occurring, whether the total dollar amount claimed is comprised of a single claim or multiple claims arising out of a single act, accident, or the same transaction or occurrence, the settlement shall be approved by both the Mayor and by a majority vote of the entire membership of the Council\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(19) - Interference with appointments or removals"
  },
  {
    "id": "recGQlsRcgRV5WBeJ",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/9/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, authority",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recRlMXr3TV1Beksw"
    ],
    "Question": "Are all executive powers of the City of Tulsa vested in the Mayor?",
    "Questions copy": "Are all executive powers of the City of Tulsa vested in the Mayor?",
    "Answer": "Yes. \"The executive and administrative powers of the City of Tulsa and any executive and administrative powers which may be conferred on the city by the Constitution or the laws of Oklahoma shall be vested in and exercised by the Mayor\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.1.) - Mayor"
  },
  {
    "id": "recFVcdi2byNdzZ69",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/9/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, authority",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recZXSJ48gtJvgOqH"
    ],
    "Question": "Are all administrative powers of the City of Tulsa vested in the Mayor?",
    "Questions copy": "Are all administrative powers of the City of Tulsa vested in the Mayor?",
    "Answer": "Yes. \"The executive and administrative powers of the City of Tulsa and any executive and administrative powers which may be conferred on the city by the Constitution or the laws of Oklahoma shall be vested in and exercised by the Mayor\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.1.) - Mayor"
  },
  {
    "id": "rece2eXCdvV2HvsZN",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "TITLE 4 - Mayor, Auditor and Council",
    "Date of Entry": "8/9/2022",
    "Article": 1,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "mayor, salary, spending",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "rectTWhDJZd2580bN"
    ],
    "Question": "What is the salary of Tulsa's Mayor?",
    "Questions copy": "What is the salary of Tulsa's Mayor?",
    "Answer": "$105,000.00. \"The Mayor of the City of Tulsa, Oklahoma, shall receive as full compensation for his or her services as Mayor, effective with the term of office commencing April 1, 2002, at 2:00 p.m., an annual salary of One Hundred Five Thousand Dollars ($105,000.00), payable as employees of the City are paid\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "Section 100. - Salary of Mayor. Ord. No. 20190"
  },
  {
    "id": "recP03LaJ4ubzuLHZ",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/9/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, authority, city council",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recuorLyU9kZV7L79"
    ],
    "Question": "Who determines the salary of Tulsa's Mayor?",
    "Questions copy": "Who determines the salary of Tulsa's Mayor?",
    "Answer": "City Council does. \"...the salary to be received by the Mayor may be changed by a majority vote of the entire membership of the Council; provided, no change in salary shall become effective prior to the commencement of the term of office next succeeding the term in which the change is made and then only in the event such change was approved prior to the general election for the next succeeding term\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.2.) - Salary"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec8mdnIICqmmYfZY",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/9/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, authority, city council, temporary mayor",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recynY04rPrmnQNFl"
    ],
    "Question": "Who acts in the Mayor's absence?",
    "Questions copy": "Who acts in the Mayor's absence?",
    "Answer": "The Temporary Mayor. \"The Mayor shall file with the City Clerk, from time to time, a designation of one or more officers or employees of the city, other than members of the Council, who shall in the order specified act as Temporary Mayor and perform the duties and exercise the powers of the Mayor during the absence or temporary disability of the Mayor or in the event of a vacancy in the office of the Mayor. The designation by the Mayor shall be subject to confirmation by a majority vote of the entire membership of the Council. Should the Mayor fail to file such designation, the Council shall designate one or more officers or employees of the city, other than members of the Council, who shall in the order specified act as Temporary Mayor\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.3.) - Absense, temporary disability, or vacancy"
  },
  {
    "id": "recC6164IsraaBl3E",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/9/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, authority",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recH07oybWsE7eMPV"
    ],
    "Question": "Who is the chief executive of the City of Tulsa?",
    "Questions copy": "Who is the chief executive of the City of Tulsa?",
    "Answer": "The Mayor of Tulsa. \"The Mayor shall be the chief executive and administrative officer of the city...\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."
  },
  {
    "id": "recODF76gUi4eK4cG",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/9/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, authority",
    "Subsection": "NA",
    "Questions": [
      "recK9xOfnsH7vmB5o"
    ],
    "Question": "Who is the administrative officer for the City of Tulsa?",
    "Questions copy": "Who is the administrative officer for the City of Tulsa?",
    "Answer": "The Mayor of Tulsa. \"The Mayor shall be the chief executive and administrative officer of the city...\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."
  },
  {
    "id": "recEljuRrFsAKzVys",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/9/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, authority",
    "Subsection": "A",
    "Questions": [
      "recNRksASdLTkDi8Y"
    ],
    "Question": "Who has the authority to establish the City of Tulsa's policy priorities?",
    "Questions copy": "Who has the authority to establish the City of Tulsa's policy priorities?",
    "Answer": "The Mayor of Tulsa is to \"identify the needs and establish the objectives and priorities of the city and make recommendations to the Council for meeting the needs and achieving the objectives\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."
  },
  {
    "id": "recTvFOFywAe0bI7Q",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/9/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, authority, authorities, boards, commissions, agencies, departments, divisions",
    "Subsection": "B",
    "Questions": [
      "rec51pSVOxxEYzQHI"
    ],
    "Question": "Who plans all boards, commissions, authorities, agencies, divisions, and departments of the City of Tulsa?",
    "Questions copy": "\"Who plans all boards, commissions, authorities, agencies, divisions, and departments of the City of Tulsa?\"",
    "Answer": "The Mayor of Tulsa.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."
  },
  {
    "id": "recaGnsE6XbLF9Fnr",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/9/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, authority, authorities, boards, commissions, agencies, departments, divisions, deadlines",
    "Subsection": "B",
    "Questions": [
      "rec6HZO4BrBbedQRd"
    ],
    "Question": "By what date must the Mayor of Tulsa file plans for organizing the city's government for the following year?",
    "Questions copy": "By what date must the Mayor of Tulsa file plans for organizing the city's government for the following year?",
    "Answer": "According to the City Charter, it prior to May 1st.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."
  },
  {
    "id": "recHGeptKIU9BWSTv",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/9/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, city council, budgets",
    "Subsection": "C",
    "Questions": [
      "rec8UQ0uUqs2KII6H"
    ],
    "Question": "Who prepares the City of Tulsa's budget?",
    "Questions copy": "Who prepares the City of Tulsa's budget?",
    "Answer": "The Mayor of Tulsa. However, per Article II Section 7.2., City Council can make changes to the budget.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."
  },
  {
    "id": "reckl4QyF8LorEFK5",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/9/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, city council, budgets",
    "Subsection": "C",
    "Questions": [
      "rec8XeueSO3E5ZOVA"
    ],
    "Question": "By what date must the Mayor of Tulsa submit the budget to City Council?",
    "Questions copy": "By what date must the Mayor of Tulsa submit the budget to City Council?",
    "Answer": "According to the City Charter, it prior to May 1st. In 2022, the Mayor's budget presentation occured on April 20th. However, informal changes to municipal deadlines of any kind are not unusual.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."
  },
  {
    "id": "recgXAwJJyz1WCcr8",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/9/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, city council, budgets, authority",
    "Subsection": "C",
    "Questions": [
      "recaXKwMMOfVhGt2t"
    ],
    "Question": "Are there tax-revenue streams in Tulsa that cannot be altered by the Mayor?",
    "Questions copy": "Are there tax-revenue streams in Tulsa that cannot be altered by the Mayor?",
    "Answer": "Yes, the 2017 Public Sales Safety Tax. No revenue derived form this tax may ever be spent for any purpose other than public safety, as defined by Title 43-I.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."
  },
  {
    "id": "rectyZWJWNz3ZqVVk",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/10/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, city council, budgets, authority",
    "Subsection": "D",
    "Questions": [
      "recdWq0G0lptcqxhA"
    ],
    "Question": "Is the Mayor required to expend the operating and capital budgets of the city?",
    "Questions copy": "Is the Mayor required to expend the operating and capital budgets of the city?",
    "Answer": "Yes, the Mayor of Tulsa is respondible for expending \"...as provided by law the funds of the city in accord with the adopted operating and capital budgets of the city\".",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."
  },
  {
    "id": "recWKnMT2wzZ9cNBV",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/10/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, city council, budgets, authority",
    "Subsection": "E",
    "Questions": [
      "rechL0MLJ9w6E0vuo"
    ],
    "Question": "Who is responsible for preserving the peace in the City of Tulsa?",
    "Questions copy": "Who is responsible for preserving the peace in the City of Tulsa?",
    "Answer": "The Mayor. The Mayor is to preserve the peace and enforce ordinances, rules, and regulations.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."
  },
  {
    "id": "reckER0CBC12lmqX7",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/10/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, city council, authority",
    "Subsection": "F",
    "Questions": [
      "rechMDG6OW5MTfQ2v"
    ],
    "Question": "Who has the authority to appoint, supervise, and remove all officers and employees of the City of Tulsa?",
    "Questions copy": "\"Who has the authority to appoint, supervise, and remove all officers and employees of the City of Tulsa?\"",
    "Answer": "The Mayor. Two exceptions to this are employees of the City Auditor and employees of City Council, who are appointed, supervised, and removed by each, respectively.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."
  },
  {
    "id": "rec0QQyDEckUK0PWw",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/10/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, mayor, city council, authority, boards, commisions, authorities, agencies",
    "Subsection": "G",
    "Questions": [
      "recko8jYikd4mw1yx"
    ],
    "Question": "How are members of boards, commissions, authorities, and agencies appointed?",
    "Questions copy": "\"How are members of boards, commissions, authorities, and agencies appointed?\"",
    "Answer": "The Mayor appoints the members of all boards, commissions, authorities, and agencies, subject to the confirmation by a majority vote of the entire membership of City Council. All those appointed must be qualified electors and maintain residence within the city limits of the City of Tulsa.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."
  },
  {
    "id": "recKs7LsDCg5mEtbS",
    "Source": "Code of Ordinance",
    "Subsource": "1989 Amended Charter",
    "Date of Entry": "8/10/2022",
    "Article": 3,
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, authorities, boards, commissions, agencies, residence",
    "Subsection": "G",
    "Questions": [
      "recnIif0ZJsNCel53"
    ],
    "Question": "Do members of authorities, boards, commissions, and agencies have to live in the city limits of the City of Tulsa?",
    "Questions copy": "\"Do members of authorities, boards, commissions, and agencies have to live in the city limits of the City of Tulsa?\"",
    "Answer": "Yes.",
    "Enterman": "Samuel",
    "Section": "(1.4.) - Executive and administrative powers and duties."
  },
  {
    "id": "recf9cdQoiDLUN4cX",
    "Source": "Tulsa 311",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, 311, parking, violation, report, customer care center",
    "Questions": [
      "rec8KDL9gKmho2qUK"
    ],
    "Question": "How do I report an abandoned or illegally parked car in Tulsa?",
    "Questions copy": "How do I report an abandoned or illegally parked car in Tulsa?",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's 311 Customer Care Center has an online form available here  for citizens to reports cars parked illegally or which appear abandoned. Providing the exact address provides the greatest chance of action being taken. If Tulsa authorities confirm a report, the car will be tagged for towing. ",
    "Enterman": "Dan"
  },
  {
    "id": "recQyzfQ6XLFyZCbH"
  },
  {
    "id": "recQQlBiZTKE9l4zo",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, spending",
    "Subsection": "7",
    "Question": "How much money does the City of Tulsa plan on spending in FY23?",
    "Answer": "The total budget is $944.9 million, an increase of $145.5 million (18.2%) over the prior year's budget. ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recxmn1tSdrrWji0v",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, operating budget, spending, payroll",
    "Subsection": "7",
    "Question": "How much money does the FY23 budget dedicate to day-to-day operations?",
    "Answer": "The operating budget is $824 million, an increase of $113.5 million (16%) over the prior year's operating budget",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recdciYrKR1fQvDYE",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, spending, capital, improvements",
    "Subsection": "7",
    "Question": "How much money does Tulsa plan to spend on improvements to its property and services in FY23? ",
    "Answer": "Tulsa funds improvements through its capital budget. Fiscal year 2022-2023 capital budget is $120.4 million. Capital funding increased by $32 million (36.2%) over the prior year's budget. ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recZ5j5ghHk4yPsQg",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "3-4, 1-6, 1-2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, economy, inflation, energy, aerospace",
    "Subsection": "7-9",
    "Question": "What economic conditions were present during the process of crafting Tulsa's FY23 budget?",
    "Answer": "According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, \"High inflation: The average price of household necessities rose 8.3% in April 2022; Increased energy costs and slowing investment, attributable to unfavorable federal policy, by gas and oil companies (major employers) into the region; Aerospace industry: Major employers in the Tulsa metro area which are promising to increase investment and employment in support infrastructure at the Tulsa airport; increased employment and average income; stagnant wage growth\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recBr4anDl0lEPb95",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "3-5, 1-6",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, spending, recruitment, public safety, law enforcement",
    "Subsection": "9-10",
    "Question": "What were some of Tulsa City government's priorities in the FY23 budget? ",
    "Answer": "Filling vacant positions by increasing salary/wage compensation and increasing the budget for recruitment efforts; Improving customer service through technology and \"a 27% increase in customer care agents taking citizen calls...about utility bills and other issues;\" Increasing public safety through focused recruitment efforts at police and fire academies, allocating public safety grant funding, and implementing a Real-time information center (RTIC) to streamline law enforcement intelligence through community surveillance. ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recje5kzVefiWAcBZ",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, revenue, general fund,",
    "Subsection": "11",
    "Question": "From where does Tulsa receive the majority of revenue used to fund its operations? ",
    "Answer": "Sales and use taxes account for 63.9% of the General Fund, which is the principal operating fund of the City. General fund revenues for FY2023 are expected to be $358.3 million",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec3VjfnvFex491az",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "5",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, reserve, emergency, stabilization, rainy day fund",
    "Subsection": "11",
    "Question": "How much money does Tulsa have put aside in case of serious economic downturn or disaster? ",
    "Answer": "The city of Tulsa's primary two reserve funds are the General Fund Emergency Operating Reserve, with a balance of $29.9 million, and the City's Economic Stabilization Reserve (aka Rainy Day Fund), with an expected balance of $12.4 million by the end of FY23. ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec0AULiNwfqk7d1A",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "6",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, spending, expenditure, payroll, general fund",
    "Subsection": "11",
    "Question": "What is the largest expenditure for Tulsa's General (day-to-day) Fund? ",
    "Answer": "The largest expenditure category is payroll, which represents 70.1% of the General Fund budget",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recWR2FDcjf8BrMi8",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "7",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, spending, resource allocation, public safety",
    "Subsection": "11",
    "Question": "Where does the City of Tulsa allocate the most significant resources? ",
    "Answer": "Public safety receives the largest allocation of resources at 53.2% of the General Fund. Public Safety includes the Police Department, Fire Department, EMS, 911 call center, and the City Prosecutor's office. ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec4VJF6iOAoHzqSw",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, water, rate, ratepayer, utility rates, infrastructure, tmua, city services",
    "Subsection": "12",
    "Question": "As a Tulsa Metropolitan Utility Authority (TMUA) ratepayer, will I have to pay more for water utility service in FY23? ",
    "Answer": "No. Through the success of an asset management program, the TMUA recommended no increase in water rates for FY23. The current rate equals $4.31 per 1,000 gallons of water used. However, the TMUA is recommending a 3% increase for FY24, partially due to increases in chemical costs.",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec2UNT6AAcsQabDW",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, sewer, utility rates, tmua, ratepayer, infrastructure, city services",
    "Subsection": "12",
    "Question": "As a Tulsa Metropolitan Utility Authority (TMUA) ratepayer, will I have to pay more for sewage treatment utility service in FY23?  ",
    "Answer": "Yes. A 7% rate increase (from $9.36 to $10.02 per 1,000 gallons of water used per single-family home) is proposed for the sanitary sewer system in FY23.  According to the FY23 budget presentation, debt and scheduled capital improvement projects (together representing nearly half the system's operating budget) are the main drivers of rate increases.",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recJynmFzYmD8vVNX",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "4",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, utility, stormwater, rates, city services",
    "Subsection": "12",
    "Question": "Are rates to maintain the City of Tulsa stormwater management system increasing in FY23? ",
    "Answer": "Yes. Rates are increasing by 8.5% (from $9.03 to 9.80 per month per residential customer) This rate increase is higher than the 7% increase that was originally proposed for FY23. Budget documents attribute the higher increase to the need for additional capital to fund improvement projects identified as high priority by a strategic planning study. ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "reckhmJOrX353i9Mp",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, sanitation, trash collection, solid waste, utility rates, city services",
    "Subsection": "13",
    "Question": "Are rates for trash collection set to increase in FY23? ",
    "Answer": "Possibly. According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, \"there are currently no changes to rates for trash service in FY23. However, ongoing discussion regarding recent developments involving refuse and recycling services will likely necessitate a rate increase for trash service in mid-FY23 or beginning FY24.\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recP7i4DgSOqsD01C",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, emsa, rates,",
    "Subsection": "13",
    "Question": "Are rates for emergency medical services (EMSA) set to increase in FY23 for Tulsa residents? ",
    "Answer": "No.  According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, \"There are currently no changes to the rate for emergency medical services in FY23.\" Households within Tulsa's city limits are currently billed $5.45 per month for EMSA, unless a household chooses to opt out and pay for EMS services out of pocket if and when necessary. ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recWC5LR9qhUy8NqT",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, capital budget, improvement projects,",
    "Subsection": "13",
    "Question": "How does Tulsa's FY23 budget reinvest the share of sales tax dedicated to the \"Improve Our Tulsa II\" program? ",
    "Answer": " According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, \"this budget includes $36.9 million in sales tax funded projects from the 2022 Improve Our Tulsa II program. This program includes funding for critical projects for Police, Fire, Parks, Citywide Public Facilities, Economic Development Infrastructure, Transit rolling stock and Capital Equipment. Priorities in this year’s budget, include $3.9 million for apparatus replacement for the Fire Department, $4.0 million to fully fund the construction of a new parking garage for the Veterans Hospital to be constructed in downtown Tulsa and $14.3 million for Capital Equipment. ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recECWiw4paLzd2j1",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "5",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, capital budget, infrastructure, city services, utility, sewer, water",
    "Subsection": "13",
    "Question": "How much is the City of Tulsa directly investing in utility system infrastructure for FY23?",
    "Answer": "The FY23 Capital Budget \"provides $49.8 million for water treatment plant work, supply system repairs, water line replacement and relocation projects. Additionally, $33.4 million will be used for sewer treatment plants, pipe replacement and other system work. Stormwater will receive $5.4 million for stormwater pipe extensions, drainage improvements associated with roadway projects, small critical drainage projects and detention pond rehabilitation.\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recSQWppxbDoaK8A1",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "5, 1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, capital budget, bonds, sales tax, elections,",
    "Subsection": "13-14",
    "Question": "How is the City of Tulsa using realized and anticipated tax revenue from the \"Vision Tulsa\" economic development capital program? ",
    "Answer": " According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, \"the City has now received over five years of collections from the sales tax approved by voters in April 2016 for the Vision Tulsa economic development capital program which is set at 0.805% for the next three years. Implementation of the project scheduling and financing plan continues. All of the planned revenue bond sales have been completed totaling $346.6 million to provide advance funding for 26 projects. The $510 million program will last 15 years. Directly funded projects total $65.3 million in the proposed budget for nine projects, with the largest allocation going toward debt service.\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec4mhtoYfiJOH3rD",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, capital budget, capital plan, improvements, city services,",
    "Subsection": "14",
    "Question": "Where is the City of Tulsa prioritizing cash investment for capital improvement projects over the next five years? ",
    "Answer": "The City's Capital Plan \"focuses on projects that should be considered for funding in the next five years, totaling $553.6 million. Close to two thirds (2/3) of the projects are renewal of existing infrastructure with the balance supporting growth. The plan is dedicated to utility system projects over the next five years as other recently approved capital programs have funded the majority of the City’s other capital needs.\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recXFbCWiCwRlhdxK",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "3, 4",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, bonds, debt, improve our tulsa, capital plan",
    "Subsection": "14",
    "Question": "How much debt does the City of Tulsa plan to incur in FY23 in the form of general obligation bonds, and for what purpose? ",
    "Answer": " According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, \"during the upcoming fiscal year, the City anticipates undertaking an issuance of $117.4 million in general obligation bonds. All funds will go toward street projects authorized in the 2014 Improve Our Tulsa program and 2020 Improve Our Tulsa II program. Some $14.8 million in bonds and loans will finance sanitary sewer and stormwater projects that include concrete pipe replacement, interceptor rehabilitation, sewer line rehabilitation and a stormwater outfall line from Hager Creek to the Arkansas River. Funds will be appropriated by budget amendment upon completion of each bond sale. Taken together these bond sales will add $132.1 million in additional funds to the capital budget, bringing the amended total to $253.5 million.\" ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recJYGcvV4OQcGDC8",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "6",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, courts, prosecutor,",
    "Subsection": "15",
    "Question": "What is the City of Tulsa doing to expand access to municipal court services? ",
    "Answer": "The City's budget for FY23 \"funds an additional prosecutor to facilitate the implementation of a night court in the municipal court system.\" City Council Chairperson, Lori Decter Wright, said in her budget address that night court will \"increase accessibility to citizens who are unable to appear before our courts during their regular working hours.\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recjruzqYATNqPcuo",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "5",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, crt, mental health, 311",
    "Subsection": "15",
    "Question": "How does Tulsa's FY23 budget address mental health services? ",
    "Answer": "In preparing this budget, City Council prioritized expanding the Community Response Team (CRT). This budget increases CRT's mobile mental health crisis response funding by $250,000 to further \"assist people suffering a mental health emergency and reduce reliance on other emergency services.\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "reczHFRDIXKOXC5hH",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "7",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, kirkpatrick heights, greenwood master plan, cultural development, preservation,",
    "Subsection": "15",
    "Question": "How does Tulsa's FY23 budget further progress on the Kirkpatrick Heights-Greenwood Master Plan? ",
    "Answer": "This budget funds $2 million toward implementation of the plan, \"which will create a vision and framework for redevelopment of 56 acres of publicly-owned property.\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recnekcBX5HkUDDJE",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "7",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, 1921 race massacre, victims, gravesites",
    "Subsection": "15",
    "Question": "How does Tulsa's FY23 budget contribute to memorializing the victims of the 1921 race massacre? ",
    "Answer": " According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, \"this budget includes $1 million to continue the search for the graves of victims of the massacre, including funds for additional excavation and DNA analysis following recommendations from technical experts.\" ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec11zagl8mwAArye",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-5, 1-3, 1-4, 1-3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, policy, compliance, oversight, audit",
    "Subsection": "16-19",
    "Question": "What are the major areas of compliance that Tulsa city officials must adhere to when crafting the annual budget?",
    "Answer": "City of Tulsa Financial policies address strategic planning, operating budget, risk management, procurement and purchasing, revenues, capital budget and improvements, long term borrowing, investments and deposits, reserves, accounting, trusts and authorities, and pension funds. ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recsVsdzxvOtaKj1s",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, strategic planning",
    "Subsection": "16",
    "Question": "What are the policies governing how Tulsa city officials must approach strategic planning? ",
    "Answer": " According to Tulsa's budget policy, \"1.) All planning activities, strategies and studies should be comprehensive and integrated on a City-wide basis and 2.) Plans, strategies and studies shall encompass multi-year time frames and be updated annually\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recy0SGcD2g825C8U",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, policies, compliance, operating budget, state law, mayor, finance department,",
    "Subsection": "16",
    "Question": "How does state law impact the City of Tulsa's budget-making process?",
    "Answer": "The Oklahoma Municipal Budget Act is the primary state statute which lays the ground rules for municipal budget-making. In Tulsa, it's the responsibility of the Mayor (through the Department of Finance) to ensure compliance with relevant state law and the timely preparation of the City of Tulsa's annual budget.  ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recSny1OqinearL17",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, policies, compliance, operating budget, state law, mayor, finance department,",
    "Subsection": "16",
    "Question": "After the fiscal year closes, how can the public find out if The City of Tulsa ends up spending more or less than the amount that's budgeted at the beginning of the fiscal year?",
    "Answer": "Firstly, the city maintains a budgetary control system to help it adhere to the budget. The public can find out how closely The City adhered to its annual budget by reviewing \"Annual Comprehensive Financial Reports\" here, which compare actual revenues and expenditures to budgeted amounts. Completed ACF reports are due no later than 6 months after the end of the fiscal year. The annual budget also shows projected versus actual revenues and expenditures for at least the most recent fiscal year. ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recBLGqEeOPWIfddv",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, policies, compliance, operating budget, state law, mayor, finance department,",
    "Subsection": "16",
    "Question": "How far in advance does the City of Tulsa try to estimate future revenue and expenses? And how do officials use that information?",
    "Answer": "As part of the budget-making process, each year the City updates revenue and expenditure projections for the next five years. Projections include estimated operating costs of future capital improvements that are included in the capital budget. The City projects its equipment replacement and maintenance needs for the next several years and will update this projection each year in order to develop a maintenance and replacement schedule. ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recWZKh5MvMZY8wKr",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, policies, compliance, operating budget, state law, mayor, finance department,",
    "Subsection": "16",
    "Question": "What happens if the City of Tulsa has surplus funds left over at the end of the fiscal year? Can officials \"roll\" those funds over into their calculations for the upcoming fiscal year?",
    "Answer": "State law and municipal policy aim to prevent a significant budget surplus or deficit by mandating that municipal officials adopt a balanced annual budget.  According to City of Tulsa budget policy, \"It shall be the goal of the City that current operating revenues will be sufficient to support current operating expenses and in no case shall more than five percent (5%) of the operating budget be supported using prior year's fund balances.\"  ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recZp3OJKf8Gar3Y0",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, policies, compliance, operating budget, utilities",
    "Subsection": "16",
    "Question": "How often do officials review pricing for utility services provided by the City of Tulsa?",
    "Answer": "Per City policy, officials examine adjustments to Water, Sewer, Stormwater and Solid Waste Disposal service rates and fees on an annual basis as an integral part of the City's budgetary process. Per budget policy, \"the City establishes all user charges and fees at a level related to the cost of providing the services\" ",
    "Section": "1-Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recvLAekpd09l4rfv",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, risk management, liability, safety, insurance",
    "Subsection": "16",
    "Question": "What are Tulsa's policies regarding how city officials manage financial risk?",
    "Answer": "Municipal budget policy states, \"1.) The City will operate a risk management program to provide for protection against loss and a reduction in exposure to liability. Such program shall include an employee safety training program to minimize financial losses to the City. 2.) The City will establish a self-insurance program to provide for protection against major losses and will purchase excess coverage insurance to cover catastrophic losses where appropriate.\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "rececYwLJe1ejHh4r",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "4",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, procurement, purchasing, spending, bidding",
    "Subsection": "16",
    "Question": "What are the policies governing procurement and purchasing for the City of Tulsa?",
    "Answer": "Municipal budget policy requires The City of Tulsa to operate a consolidated Purchasing and Procurement System, which \"shall encourage full and open competition\" on all purchases and sales of surplus property via competitive bidding whenever possible.",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recuJXd0fSClM63fh",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "5, 1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, revenue, enterprise funds, pilot, utilities ",
    "Subsection": "16-17",
    "Question": "What kind of municipal revenue qualifies as \"enterprise funds\" in Tulsa's annual budget?",
    "Answer": "Enterprise funds include the operating and capital funds of various city services (such as utilities) where the public is charged a fee based on usage. The city's general fund receives revenue from enterprise funds annually via a payment-in-lieu-of-taxes scheme. Other enterprise funds include emergency medical services, solid waste collection, and the sale of leases on city-owned property.  Enterprise funds contribute to the City's goal of maintaining \"a diversified and stable revenue system to shelter it from short-run fluctuations in any one revenue source,\" as outlined in municipal budget policy. ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recdYT6Ouo5pUOAqn",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "5, 2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, debt, revenue, delinquency, credit, litigation",
    "Subsection": "16-18",
    "Question": "How does the City of Tulsa manage receivable debt owed by outside parties?",
    "Answer": "According to municipal budget policy regarding revenue management, \"The City of Tulsa will neither begin business activity nor continue to engage in business activity with an entity that owes the City funds from a delinquent debt. The City, at its discretion, may choose to extend credit for certain obligations. However, \"if payment is not timely, the City reserves the right to refuse future credit as well as take necessary legal action to obtain payment of the debt and collection costs.\" ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "reczILDoYEhqozsfE",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, capital budget, improvements, bonds, debt, financing",
    "Subsection": "17",
    "Question": "How does the City of Tulsa fund its capital improvement projects?",
    "Answer": "According to municipal budget policy,  \"The City shall maintain a balanced mix of financing for funding capital projects, including pay-as-you-go, grants and debt, without excessive reliance on any one source. No capital project which does not comply with the provisions of and is not contained in the currently approved Capital Improvements Program shall be funded.\"  ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recGYGbxLV4MEqlhw",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, capital budget, improvements, cip",
    "Subsection": "17",
    "Question": "What criteria do Tulsa city officials use to evaluate potential new capital improvement projects? ",
    "Answer": "According to municipal budget policy,  \"capital projects will be scheduled based on the following criteria: The project has been certified by the Planning Commission as being in accordance with City plans; The project will alleviate a service deficiency or replace a deteriorated and/or non-functioning facility; Federal or state law requires it to be done; Federal or state matching funds are available for the project; A Federal or state agency will construct the facility at no cost to the City; The project will encourage economic development; The project is needed to solve an emergency situation; The project will improve the quality of life in the City's neighborhoods.\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec9C7mhEb4kKWWMa",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, capital budget, improvements, cip, public comment",
    "Subsection": "17",
    "Question": "Do Tulsa residents have a say in what capital improvement projects get approved? ",
    "Answer": "Yes.  Public hearings are held before deciding what projects to include in any multi-year capital program, which requires approval by the City Council in the form of an adopted ordinance as part of the annual budget process. ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "reclGHmr1umPC1K2m",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, borrowing, debt, bonds, financing",
    "Subsection": "17",
    "Question": "Under what circumstances is it acceptable for the City of Tulsa to incur debt by issuing bonds? ",
    "Answer": " According to Tulsa budget policy, \"General Obligation and Revenue Bonds shall only be issued for capital improvements and maintenance, or expenditures related thereto. Revenue bonds shall be used to finance capital improvements wherever possible. No operating expenses shall be funded using any form of long term financing.\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recPEN3KFv52Sao0d",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, borrowing, debt, bonds, financing",
    "Subsection": "17",
    "Question": "What's the maximum amount of debt that the City of Tulsa can carry at any given time?",
    "Answer": "Municipal policy prohibits total debt from exceeding \"such levels as to cause the City's credit rating to be impaired, and in all cases the City shall take such actions and adopt such policies and procedures as necessary to maintain a rating equal to at least AA for general obligation debt.\" Additionally,  \"In no event shall the net general obligation debt exceed twenty-five percent (25%) of the net assessed market valuation of the taxable property of the City of Tulsa as established by the County Assessor.\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recnN0rAgceKpAN0y",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, borrowing, debt, bonds, financing",
    "Subsection": "17",
    "Question": "What's the maximum timeframe over which the City of Tulsa can finance projects using debt?",
    "Answer": "According to Tulsa budget policy, \"projects financed through the issuance of debt shall not be financed for a period that exceeds the expected useful life of the project and in no event shall the term of any debt exceed twenty-five (25) years.\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recEnWVXTLtQXcQYi",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, borrowing, debt, bonds, financing",
    "Subsection": "18",
    "Question": "How must Tulsa city officials structure the sale of municipal bonds? ",
    "Answer": "According to Tulsa budget policy, \"bond sales shall be structured to achieve level debt service payments to the extent possible, taking into consideration the costs of such financings. Either variable or fixed rate financing may be used, subject to applicable laws, depending on the cost benefit to the City of each option. Competitive sale shall be used for all general obligation debt issuances of the City of Tulsa. Negotiated or competitive sale may be used for revenue bonds.\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recZKZJLKc2oMJxM5",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, investment, finance department",
    "Subsection": "18",
    "Question": "Who is responsible for managing the City of Tulsa's investment portfolio? ",
    "Answer": "According to Tulsa budget policy, \"responsibility for the investment program of the City shall be vested with the Director of Finance who shall establish an investment program consistent with an adopted investment policy.\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recLeUQ3raHa13c5i",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, investment, finance department",
    "Subsection": "18",
    "Question": "What criteria do City of Tulsa officials use to evaluate investment opportunities for public funds?",
    "Answer": "According to Tulsa budget policy, \"it shall be the objective of the City of Tulsa to pool and invest public funds in accordance with current legislation and the Charter of the City of Tulsa. Criteria for investing shall adhere to the following order of priority: (1) Safety, (2) Liquidity, (3) Yield.\"",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recO8cP3NdBdSKxuR",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, investment, finance department",
    "Subsection": "18",
    "Question": "How does the City of Tulsa manage its cash flow? ",
    "Answer": "Through a cash flow management system \"which includes the preparation of a cash flow analysis of all funds on a regular basis. Disbursement, collection, and deposit of all funds will be scheduled to ensure maximum investment return and cash availability subject to the City's investment policies. The cash flow management system shall ensure the City can offset significant downturns in revenues which could not have been reasonably foreseen and provide sufficient working capital and cash for daily financial needs,\" according to Tulsa budget policy.",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recBdVm1zFO6PsxZe",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, auditing, accounting ",
    "Subsection": "18",
    "Question": "Does the City of Tulsa have safeguards to prevent and/or identify misappropriation of public funds? ",
    "Answer": "Yes. City of Tulsa policy mandates that all financial transactions \"be audited annually by a recognized independent certified public accounting firm and such audit results shall include a management letter detailing areas where improvement is needed. A firm to perform such audit shall be chosen not more than once every five (5) years.\" Additionally, \"the City shall prepare and issue an official Comprehensive Annual Financial Report no later than six (6) months following the fiscal year-end in accordance with Government Finance Officer's Association and Governmental Accounting Standards Board principles and standards. The City of Tulsa shall also must maintain an accounting control environment to help ensure proper authorization for financial transactions and proper procedures for safeguarding assets.\" ",
    "Section": "1- Policies"
  },
  {
    "id": "recvmOUHdz6STY4NR",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "Figure 1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, revenue, taxes, enterprise, licenses, permits, fees, fines, forfeiture, investment",
    "Subsection": "1",
    "Question": "What are the sources of revenue for the City of Tulsa? ",
    "Answer": "The City of Tulsa categorizes its revenue streams in three broad categories: Taxes, which account for 54% of revenue; Enterprise funds (the profit from goods and services sold by the City to the public for a fee), which account for 35% of total municipal revenue; and \"other\" revenues, which account for 11%. \"Other\" revenues include proceeds from issuing licenses and permits, state/federal/county grants, \"general government\" revenue, fines and forfeitures, investment income, and \"miscellaneous\" revenue. ",
    "Section": "2- Executive Summary"
  },
  {
    "id": "recjjSuWP6imA0NCU",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2-5, 1-2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, revenue, taxes, sales tax, use tax, franchise tax, hotel/motel tax, ad valorem tax",
    "Subsection": "5-6",
    "Question": "What gets taxed by the City of Tulsa? ",
    "Answer": "The City of Tulsa collects taxes in five major categories: Sales taxes, Use taxes, Franchise taxes/Right of Way user fees, Hotel/Motel taxes, and Ad Valorem Taxes. ",
    "Section": "2-Executive Summary"
  },
  {
    "id": "receUqlsB7kmro0gA",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, revenue, taxes, sales tax ",
    "Subsection": "5",
    "Question": "How does the City of Tulsa tax private sales and what is the money used for? ",
    "Answer": "The City of Tulsa taxes sales at 3.65%. 2% goes into the General Fund to support city operations. 1.6% is split between the 2019 \"Improve our Tulsa\" program (.45%) and the \"Vision Tulsa\" (1.15%) funds. The remaining .05% is held in the city's Economic Stabilization Reserve. ",
    "Section": "2-Executive Summary"
  },
  {
    "id": "recye1yVU9QAgW6Pc",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "4",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, revenue, taxes, Use tax",
    "Subsection": "5",
    "Question": "What is a \"Use Tax\" and how does the City of Tulsa use that money in its budget?",
    "Answer": "The City of Tulsa applies a 3.65% tax to personal property which is purchased outside the State of Oklahoma and used within the city. 3.1% goes into the General Fund to support city operations. The remaining 0.55% is allocated to the 2016 \"Tulsa Economic Vision\" Fund. ",
    "Section": "2-Executive Summary"
  },
  {
    "id": "recc6PgBgqZcFBbpZ",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "5",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, revenue, taxes, franchise tax, right of way user fees",
    "Subsection": "5",
    "Question": "Who pays franchise taxes/right of way user fees to the City of Tulsa? ",
    "Answer": "The City of Tulsa collects taxes and fees from utility service providers and telecommunications companies that build and maintain infrastructure on city-owned rights of way in order to deliver their service to residents and businesses. Revenue from this tax scheme is projected to be $30.4 million in FY23. Almost 50% of that revenue is paid, collectively, by Oklahoma Natural Gas and Public Service Company of Oklahoma.  ",
    "Section": "2-Executive Summary"
  },
  {
    "id": "recLPgdK51RybNzzH",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, revenue, taxes, hotel/motel taxes",
    "Subsection": "6",
    "Question": "What's the tax rate on hotel and motel bookings in the City of Tulsa? ",
    "Answer": "The City of Tulsa taxes hotel and motel room bookings at 5%. ",
    "Section": "2-Executive Summary"
  },
  {
    "id": "recCgsZTKzAfum1KR",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, revenue, taxes, ad valorem tax, tax levy, bonds, debt, liability, lawsuit",
    "Subsection": "6",
    "Question": "What is an \"Ad Valorem\" tax and what does the City of Tulsa use that money for? ",
    "Answer": "Ad Valorem is Latin for \"according to value.\" In practice, an ad valorem tax in the State of Oklahoma is a property tax. According to the State Constitution, Tulsa must receive sufficient ad valorem taxes each year to make scheduled payments on municipal debt and to cover the value of court judgements granted to plaintiffs who successfully sue the city. Ad valorem tax revenue is deposited into the city's \"sinking fund\" specifically for those purposes. The sinking fund in not treated as a part of Tulsa's operating budget. ",
    "Section": "2-Executive Summary"
  },
  {
    "id": "recL5lyZbOHnUhjzm",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "4",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, revenue, taxes, state taxes",
    "Subsection": "6",
    "Question": "How much revenue does the City of Tulsa receive from state taxes on vehicle licenses, liquor, gasoline and tobacco? ",
    "Answer": "For FY23, the City of Tulsa projects receiving an $8.1 million share of state tax receipts. ",
    "Section": "2-Executive Summary"
  },
  {
    "id": "recDUavs6KTL1mtQm",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "5",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, state grants, federal grants, municipal aid",
    "Subsection": "6",
    "Question": "How much funding does the City of Tulsa receive in the form of state and federal grants? ",
    "Answer": "For FY23, the City of Tulsa projects receiving $7.3 million in grant funding from the state and federal governments. ",
    "Section": "2-Executive Summary"
  },
  {
    "id": "recC17ZRE1wBVKZcx",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "5",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, spending, strategic planning",
    "Subsection": "24",
    "Question": "How do the Mayor of Tulsa and City Council describe their long-term goals for improving quality of life? ",
    "Answer": "According to FY23 budget documents, Tulsa city government's top three goals for the next several years are to \"increase the number of uniformed police officers, build cash reserves, and provide annually satisfactory performance increases for the city's workforce.\" Additional goals include to: \"combat homelessness, increase transit access to jobs, improve neighborhood conditions, continue work on equity indicators, economic development and commercial revitalization, tourism and destination districts\"",
    "Section": "2-Executive Summary"
  },
  {
    "id": "recicaQbiun0IJOPT",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "4, 5",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, municipal court, legal department ",
    "Subsection": "3",
    "Question": "How does Tulsa's FY23 budget expand municipal court services?",
    "Answer": "This budget adds a new \"configuration coordinator\" position (at a salary of $80,000) to the court's staff to manage the online databases used by court officials and the public. This budget also includes funding for \"mass communication software that utilizes text and email reminders about upcoming court dates and payments due.\" As part of the effort to start up a night court, the FY23 budget also funds hiring an additional public defender specifically to cover expanded hours. Prior to this budget, the municipal court received Coronavirus relief funding \"that will support outreach programs, facility improvements, Mental Health Initiatives and Organizational Development. CRF funding will also fund additional support personnel, including \"administrative support, court reporters, and Spanish greeters.\"",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recsyyQ9mTAm2A8Kh",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "4",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, police, law enforcement, public safety, personnel ",
    "Subsection": "10",
    "Question": "How many sworn police officers work for the City of Tulsa? ",
    "Answer": "As of beginning of FY23, Tulsa PD employed 943 sworn police officers. That includes: 743 police officers, 82 sergeants, 83 lieutenants, 23 captains, 9 majors, and 3 deputy chiefs. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recjNNz1MNSrDfy4W",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "5",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, police, law enforcement, public safety, personnel, training",
    "Subsection": "6",
    "Question": "Is the City of Tulsa hiring more police officers? ",
    "Answer": "Yes. Although the total number of sworn police officers did not change from FY22 to FY23, The Mayor of Tulsa and City Council consider police recruitment to be one of the city's highest priorities. In FY23, the police department has $4.5 million in funding to enroll and train 90 cadets at the police academy. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recUyekUVeGgHuyu7",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, police, law enforcement, public safety, spending",
    "Subsection": "7",
    "Question": "How much money does it take to run the Tulsa Police Department? ",
    "Answer": "For FY23, Tulsa PD has an operating budget of $144.8 million, and an additional $4.5 million budget for new and/or upgraded equipment and technology. The PD's total budget increased by $26.7 million (approx. 21.7%) from FY22 to 23. The largest share of police department funding, $118.3 million or 79.2%, comes from the City of Tulsa's general fund. The balance of funding comes from dedicated sales taxes and court fees. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "rechrb5jPCqxKUShV",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "3, 1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, police, law enforcement, public safety, spending",
    "Subsection": "7-8",
    "Question": "Why did funding for the Tulsa Police Department increase by more than 20% in one year? ",
    "Answer": "Some of the largest line item changes in the FY23 police operating budget include: an additional $14.78 million for benefits and compensation, $3.4 million to replace 80 marked police vehicles, $3.4 million in overtime compensation, a one-time appropriation of $1.2 million to replace tasers and associated equipment, and $1.2 million for internal equipment maintenance. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recYo5G8KM1NApHye",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, fire department, public safety, spending",
    "Subsection": "12",
    "Question": "Is the Tulsa Fire Department hiring members? ",
    "Answer": "Yes. The Tulsa Fire Department is enrolling 30 cadets in the training academy in FY23 at a cost of $1.28 million and plans to train an additional 30 in FY24. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recCS2AAOglPncxgu",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, fire department, public safety, spending, ",
    "Subsection": "12",
    "Question": "How much does it cost to run the Tulsa Fire Department? ",
    "Answer": "The Tulsa Fire Department operating budget for FY23 totals $91.7 million dollars, with an additional $3.9 million dollars for upgrades to equipment and technology. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recIOjrOr71ffQqTJ",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "4, 1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, fire department, public safety, spending",
    "Subsection": "11-12",
    "Question": "Why did funding for Tulsa Fire Department increase by $10 million in FY23 instead of remaining stable (as was initially planned)?",
    "Answer": "The FY23 Fire Department operating budget includes a $5.1 million increase in benefits and compensation in order to \"address recruitment and retention issues.\" Additionally, from FY22 to FY23, the fire department's operating capital increased from $610,000 to $4.5 million. According to the Department highlights section of the FY23 municipal budget, \"the Tulsa Fire Department was awarded a grant to reimburse the cost of sixty new firefighters for three years. As a result, Tulsa Fire Department will utilize those savings to fund operational support replacements and accelerate the replacement of needed fleet equipment in FY23 through FY25\"",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "reclsGUfoye3Fot1c",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, fire department, public safety, personnel",
    "Subsection": "14",
    "Question": "How many people does the Tulsa Fire Department employ?",
    "Answer": "The fire department's budget provides for a 743-person workforce. Of that, 725 staff are first responders or inspection/prevention professionals and 18 hold administrative/support roles. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec33ZFbSioBXwKiq",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, parks and recreation",
    "Subsection": "21",
    "Question": "How many parks are there in the City of Tulsa? ",
    "Answer": "According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, \"the City of Tulsa manages 135 parks covering roughly 6,553 acres. This includes two nature centers, seven community centers including WaterWorks Art Studio, 57 miles of walking trails, two skate parks, three dog parks and five swimming pools. In addition, there are 227 sports fields (132 diamond fields and 95 rectangular fields), 99 playgrounds, 94 tennis courts, 8 pickleball courts, 29 basketball courts and 36 half basketball courts, 13 water playgrounds, 18 splash pads and 96 picnic shelters, four golf courses and eight disc golf courses.\" ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recsNKRxT7U2KJTKu",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, parks and recreation",
    "Subsection": "22",
    "Question": "How much money does Tulsa spend on parks and recreation? ",
    "Answer": "The total parks and recreation budget for FY23 is $18.7 million. The budget includes $14 million in operation funds and $4.7 million for capital projects, equipment and upgrades. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recDFYvJFIJG6Xp8T",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-5",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, parks and recreation, personnel",
    "Subsection": "24",
    "Question": "How many people are employed across Tulsa's parks and recreation facilities? ",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's parks and recreation facilities employ 175 people in total. 130 positions are full-time. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recub5PtvsEp7NUBd",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-3, 1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, parks and recreation, river parks, tulsa county",
    "Subsection": "25-26",
    "Question": "How does the City of Tulsa manage its parks along the Arkansas River? ",
    "Answer": "River parks, including metro trails along the river and the Turkey Mountain Urban Wilderness area are supported by shared investment between the City of Tulsa and Tulsa County. The $748,000 in resources allocated for River Parks are utilized for operational support to maintain the trails, Turkey Mountain Urban Wilderness and rest room facilities along the trail system.",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recQlZGN1Dwf7aruQ",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, parks and recreations, contracts",
    "Subsection": "29",
    "Question": "Does the City of Tulsa outsource for management of any city-owned facilities? ",
    "Answer": "Yes. The City has engaged in management agreements for the operations of City owned culture and recreation facilities. These facilities include the Tulsa Zoo, Mohawk Soccer Complex, Page and Mohawk golf courses, Performing Arts Center, and the Gilcrease Museum. The Parks and Recreation Department is responsible for the oversight for each of the management agreements. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec3T93loB45dcKpT",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, working in neighborhoods, win, social services, housing, public safety, quality of life, development",
    "Subsection": "33",
    "Question": "What services are provided by the city's Working in Neighborhoods department?",
    "Answer": "Housing – to assist homeowners with emergency housing repairs and rehabilitation; prevent early institutionalization of the elderly; create incentives to develop affordable housing; and address substandard housing and revitalize housing through property maintenance and demolition. Neighborhood Services – increase opportunities for neighborhood reinvestment; serve as the contact between residents and the City to coordinate the delivery of public/private resources; and establish neighborhood associations and/or block groups to stabilize and improve neighborhood\nenvironments. Neighborhood Investigations – promote voluntary compliance and enforcement of City nuisance codes; provide a fair and unbiased enforcement program to correct nuisance violations and land use requirements. Animal Welfare – operate the animal shelter and field services to provide a safe, healthy environment for companion animals; support and empower residents for successful pet ownership and educate about codes. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "rechreUyYOvlhkTNU",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, working in neighborhoods, win, social services, housing, public safety, quality of life, development",
    "Subsection": "34",
    "Question": "How much funding goes to support Tulsa's Working in Neightborhoods department?",
    "Answer": "The WIN department's total funding for FY23 is $9.5 million. The majority of funding comes from the City's general fund, while $1.3 million comes from intergovernmental Community Development Block Grants which mainly support housing initiatives. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recAEf8FGsOkjAJfB",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "4",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, working in neighborhoods, win, social services, housing, public safety, quality of life, development",
    "Subsection": "33",
    "Question": "What is the City of Tulsa doing to improve quality of life at the neighborhood level? ",
    "Answer": "Through the Working in Neighborhoods department, Tulsa is allocating an additional $200,000 to address nuisance abatement needs for an FY23 total of $1.078 million. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recJMGPFR7yZFPGB2",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-5",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, working in neighborhoods, win, social services, housing, public safety, quality of life, development, personnel",
    "Subsection": "35",
    "Question": "How many people are employed by Tulsa's Working in Neighborhoods department? ",
    "Answer": "As of beginning of FY23, the WIN department budget authorizes 83 positions. Majority of positions are engaged in neighborhood investigations (30) and animal welfare (40). ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recW218W66wLYv6EZ",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, development services, permits, development, licenses, inspection",
    "Subsection": "36",
    "Question": "What agency of city government is responsible for approving development permits? ",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's Development Services Department is responsible for implementation of the City's development permitting process, including infrastructure and building plan review and inspection services for all private development within the City of Tulsa.",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recjt5RegBjbATLb2",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "4",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, development services, permits, development, licenses, inspection",
    "Subsection": "36",
    "Question": "What is the City of Tulsa doing to keep up with demand for building permit and licensing services? ",
    "Answer": "The FY23 municipal budget includes $88,000 in new funding for the Department of Development Services to hire two additional office assistants to \"meet permit licenses and\ncustomer requests.\" The City is also spending $334,000 to replace 11 SUV's used by inspection staff. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recxLRb6eLFaaYqVh",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, development services, permits, development, licenses, inspection",
    "Subsection": "38",
    "Question": "How many employees does the City of Tulsa have working to facilitate construction and development applications? ",
    "Answer": "The City's Development Services Department budgets for 72 staff. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recslByrKRT4t6Xeo",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, tulsa authority for economic opportunity, development, tax increment finance districts, redevelopment, affordable housing, small business",
    "Subsection": "39",
    "Question": "How does the City of Tulsa manage its efforts to spur economic growth? ",
    "Answer": "Public efforts to drive economic growth in Tulsa are primarily organized through the Tulsa Authority for Economic Opportunity (TAEO). According to the Authority, their mission is to \"create and manage public assets and resources to drive economic growth.\" ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recJCaK6NdAKKs7LG",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, tulsa authority for economic opportunity, development, taeo, tax increment finance districts, redevelopment, affordable housing, small business",
    "Subsection": "39",
    "Question": "What services are provided by the Tulsa Authority for Economic Opportunity? ",
    "Answer": "TAEO services include: serving as the lead administrative entity for economic and community development services for the City of Tulsa; Managing the City’s Tax Increment Finance (TIF) Districts; Managing and supporting the City’s bond-financed economic development programs; Executing land acquisition and disposition to leverage private development and redevelopment; Leading asset optimization strategy related to major economic development assets; Managing Downtown Development and Redevelopment loan programs; Managing the Affordable Housing Trust Fund and other housing development programs and incentives; Managing outreach, education, and utilization monitoring for the City’s Small Business Enterprise program.",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recEsk3QprSwTZRfC",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "4-5",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, engineering services, development, public ways, pso, capital improvement, stormwater management, utility, spending, ",
    "Subsection": "47",
    "Question": "What projects are in the pipeline for the City of Tulsa's Engineering Services Department? ",
    "Answer": "Using $2.6 million in franchise fees collected by the City from the Public Service Company of Oklahoma, Tulsa's Engineering Services department is beginning the process to coordinate burial of power lines located on public rights of way. The department is also increasing staff in order to implement phase two of the City's Stormwater Utility Enterprise Initiative, in conjunction with the Streets and Stormwater department. Phase two involves scheduling and implementation of capital projects, using information from inspections conducted in phase one. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "receYoeVDSLtNk3bD",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "5, 3, 1-4",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, engineering services, personnel",
    "Subsection": "47-48, 50 ",
    "Question": "How many personnel are employed in Tulsa's Engineering Services Department?",
    "Answer": "The Engineering Services Department employs 166 people. The department allocated $650,000 in FY23 to increase staff in preparation for several stormwater management projects. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recfFklqjSPOZUvLi",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, streets and stormwater, rights of way, traffic, land management, recycling, tulsa authority for the recovery of energy, ",
    "Subsection": "51",
    "Question": "What City services are overseen by the Streets and Stormwater Department? ",
    "Answer": "The Streets and Stormwater Department’s primary areas of responsibility are street maintenance and rights-of-way inspections, traffic control, stormwater, land management, refuse and recycling service through the Tulsa Authority for the Recovery of Energy (TARE). ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec8kAYqf11qIi3XR",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, streets and stormwater, traffic, graffiti, ",
    "Subsection": "51",
    "Question": "What is the City of Tulsa doing in FY23 to improve roadways? ",
    "Answer": "The streets and Stormwater Department is receiving $1.9 million in the FY23 budget to \"manage contracted services for utility pole removal, traffic light conversion and expansion, and median maintenance and beautification. Additionally, two inspectors have been funded to monitor streets and maintenance zones for such needed efforts as well as 2 crew members to remediate graffiti.\" ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recJ6ZHM0T5TzDQ7r",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, streets and stormwater, cdbg, public ways, utilities, tare, tmua, general fund, spending",
    "Subsection": "52",
    "Question": "How much does the City of Tulsa spend on maintaining its streets and stormwater infrastructure?",
    "Answer": "The FY23 operating budget for Tulsa's Streets and Stormwater Department totals $81.4 million. Funding for the department comes from a variety of sources, including transfers from: the City's general fund (21%), the Stormwater enterprise fund (29%), and the City's operating budget for sanitation services (38.9%)",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recsBi7yVE1nFXdtk",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-5",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, streets and stormwater, personnel",
    "Subsection": "54",
    "Question": "How many people are employed in Tulsa's Streets and Stormwater Department? ",
    "Answer": "The FY23 budget for the Streets and Stormwater Department authorizes 377 total positions. However, only 328 positions are considered full-time. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recKpybyLw5NnpoFy",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, water and sewer",
    "Subsection": "55",
    "Question": "Where does the City of Tulsa's drinking water come from? ",
    "Answer": "Tulsa’s drinking water comes from two sources: Lakes Spavinaw and Eucha on Spavinaw Creek and Lake Oologah on the Verdigris River. Lakes Spavinaw and Eucha are owned and operated by the City. Lake Oologah is operated by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers. A third emergency source of water is available from Lake Hudson on Grand River. Water is treated at two treatment plants: Mohawk and A.B. Jewell and provided to customers through a water distribution system. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recL6ooA8dREUS6O7",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, water and sewer, budget, spending",
    "Subsection": "56",
    "Question": "How much does the City of Tulsa spend to provide drinking water and treat wastewater? ",
    "Answer": "The FY23 operating budget for Tulsa's Water and Sewer Department totals $150.5 million, a 16.4% increase since FY22's budget. Officials attributed the budget increase to higher costs of chemicals and electric rates. Additionally, the Water and Sewer Department is budgeting $5.8 million for capital improvement projects in FY23. Operating revenue for the Sewer and Water Department mainly comes from service fees charged to users. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec2cjeClvRPH1KZp",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-5, 1-4",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, water and sewer, budget, personnel",
    "Subsection": "59-60",
    "Question": "How many people are employed across Tulsa's Water and Sewer system? ",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's Water and Sewer Department budget authorizes 670 positions in FY23. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recM731SKk31fTNES",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, transit, transportation, bus, broken arrow, jenks, sand springs",
    "Subsection": "61",
    "Question": "How far does Tulsa Transit service area reach? ",
    "Answer": "Tulsa Transit provides public transportation serving residents in the City of Tulsa, Broken Arrow, Jenks, and Sand Springs. These services include fixed route bus service, ADA paratransit services for persons with disabilities, late evening service “Nightline,” and commuter bus service.",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recTgKfvzAst2in78",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "Using $2.6 million in franchise fees collected by the City from the Public Service Company of Oklahoma, Tulsa's Engineering Services department is beginning the process to coordinate burial of power lines located on public rights of way. The department is also increasing staff in order to implement phase two of the City's Stormwater Utility Enterprise Initiative, in conjuction with the Streets and Stormwater department. Phase two involves scheduling and implementation of capital projects, using information from inspections conducted in phase one. ",
    "Subsection": "62",
    "Question": "How much does it cost to operate Tulsa's transit system? ",
    "Answer": "Tulsa Transit's FY23 operating budget totals $11.3 million. The transit system's total budget also includes $1.2 million for capital projects. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec96lXqD2wKtxbGE",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, elected officials, mayor, administration, compensation",
    "Subsection": "66",
    "Question": "How much funding goes to the office of Tulsa's Mayor? ",
    "Answer": "The FY23 operating budget for the mayor's office totals $1.5 million, which represents a $104,000 increase from FY22. That increase was attributed to benefit and compensation adjustments. The Mayor's office FY23 budget also includes $1.6 million for capital spending, however the adopted FY23 budget didn't include a capital spending plan. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recACOs6HAE3haGOC",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, elected officials, mayor, administration, personnel",
    "Subsection": "67",
    "Question": "How many people work directly under the Mayor of Tulsa? ",
    "Answer": "Besides the mayor, 14 people are employed in their office. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recErWyBAxSKM54TK",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, elected officials, city auditor",
    "Subsection": "65",
    "Question": "What is the role of the City Auditor of Tulsa?",
    "Answer": "The Internal Auditor is responsible for keeping an independent watch over City operations and resources to ensure citizens’ resources are safeguarded and efficiently and effectively applied to the intended purposes. The mission of the City Auditor is to provide accountability of city government. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recEm5cB56SXNSaA7",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, elected officials, city auditor, operations",
    "Subsection": "68",
    "Question": "How much funding goes to supporting the City Auditor's office? ",
    "Answer": "The FY23 operating budget for the City Auditor totals $1.4 million. Funding increased by $171,000 since FY22, which included: $109,000 in salary adjustments, and $42,000 for technology. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recF3vzBOJPYUp6TS",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, elected officials, city auditor, personnel",
    "Subsection": "69",
    "Question": "How many people work in the Tulsa City Auditor's office?",
    "Answer": "Excluding the City Auditor themself, 11 people work in their office. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recPhUZLkFCcGd6Z6",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, elected officials, city council",
    "Subsection": "70",
    "Question": "Does Tulsa City Council approve a budget for itself? ",
    "Answer": "Yes. City Council's budget for FY23 totals $1.6 million. Council is funded entirely from the City's General Fund. Council's budget increased by $259,000 since FY22, with changes including: an additional $163,000 for compensation, $48,000 for a position that council deferred in FY22, and $15,000 to fund councilors' travel to conferences.",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recBZASCfvN0R7iEH",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, elected officials, city council, personnel",
    "Subsection": "71",
    "Question": "How many people are employed to support Tulsa City council?",
    "Answer": "Excluding the 9 city councilors, Council's budget includes funding for 14 staff. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "reczlO9LM6EEa0Bfb",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, legal department, litigation, attorney",
    "Subsection": "72",
    "Question": "How does the City of Tulsa handle its legal affairs? ",
    "Answer": "The City Attorney and the Legal department provide all the City’s municipal legal services. The department prepares and reviews ordinances, resolutions, executive orders, and contracts, and handles litigation, claims and controversies involving the City. Attorneys give advice and legal opinions to the City's elected officials, officers, employees, and to City boards, trusts, authorities, and agencies.",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recTJu0Cgr0faMn2N",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, legal department, compensation",
    "Subsection": "73",
    "Question": "How much does Tulsa spend on its legal department? ",
    "Answer": "The FY23 budget for Tulsa's legal department totals $4.8 million. Funding increased by $693,000 since FY22, including: an additional $347,000 for compensation, and $289,000 to fund two new attorneys and a paralegal. 99% of legal department funding comes from the City's General Fund. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recgmDbQw6dFAhpRq",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, legal department, personnel",
    "Subsection": "74",
    "Question": "How many attorneys does Tulsa employ in-house?",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's Legal Department FY23 budget includes funding for 23 City Attorneys, as well as 12 administrative/support personnel. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "reciRpdWDsrGNM5Ri",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, human resources, employment, personnel",
    "Subsection": "75",
    "Question": "How does the City of Tulsa manage its workforce? ",
    "Answer": "Through the Human Resources Department. Major responsibilities include: Employment, Compensation and Classification, Occupational Health, Workers’ Compensation, Employee Development, Insurance and Retirement Services. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recoA04OBfQIDnGd9",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, human resources, employment, personnel",
    "Subsection": "76",
    "Question": "How much does it cost to fund Tulsa's Human Resources department?",
    "Answer": "FY23 funding for Tulsa's HR department totals $30.3 million, including funding for workers' compensation ($5.9 million) and employee benefits ($19.6 million) which are facilitated through the department. Excluding that funding leaves $4.5 million for HR department operations. HR department funding decreased by $1.8 million since FY22, reflecting a savings on insurance costs which was achieved through changing vendors. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recnmWYfJtuXxNQIm",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, human resources, personnel",
    "Subsection": "78",
    "Question": "How many people work in Tulsa's Human Resources Department?",
    "Answer": "The City's Human Resources Department FY23 budget authorizes 44 positions. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "reckI7m6NJXcqdHXj",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-5",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, incog, indian nations council of governments, planning, aging services, grants, development",
    "Subsection": "81",
    "Question": "What services does the City of Tulsa receive through its membership in the Indian Nations Council of Governments?",
    "Answer": "Through the City Government's voluntary participation in INCOG, Tulsa receives assistance with city planning, transportation planning and programs, environmental and energy planning, community and economic development, aging services, and public safety. INCOG also acts as a liaison between its member governments and superior (state and federal) governments, advocating for and monitoring legislation that impacts the Tulsa metro area. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "reckmijYgmXjvap88",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "6, 1-3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, incog, indian nations council of governments, planning, grants, development, tulsa metro, tmapc",
    "Subsection": "81-82",
    "Question": "How much funding does The City of Tulsa contribute to the Indian Nations Council of Governments? ",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's FY23 contribution to INCOG is budgeted at $3.3 million. According to budget documents, \"resources allocated to INCOG will support services provided to the City of Tulsa for the following: land development reviews for TMAPC in accordance with the comprehensive plan; identifying and securing Federal and State transportation resources; identifying and securing Federal funding for economic development; and for the Destination District and Vibrant Neighborhoods programs.\"",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec90KZMt9zBbafPU",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, finance department, accounting, finance, investment, debt, grant funding, ",
    "Subsection": "83",
    "Question": "What are the main functions of Tulsa's Finance Department? ",
    "Answer": "According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, Finance Department operations are carried out by eight divisions: administration, budget and planning, treasury, purchasing, accounting, utility services, City Clerk, and the Office of Performance, Strategy and Innovation",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec1I9ucfLbU53ah7",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, finance department, accounting, finance, investment, debt, grant funding, ",
    "Subsection": "83",
    "Question": "What services does Tulsa's Finance Department provide to officials and the public? ",
    "Answer": "According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, services include: \"accounting for all revenues, expenditures, assets and liabilities; preparing the annual budgets and the capital plan; processing purchase requests; striving for the highest-possible return on the city's investment portfolio; paying all the city's bills, developing and implementing financial policies, administrating the City's debt programs, maintaining the billing system for utilities, and analyzing financial data to inform officials' decision making. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recNVMTWcXU7AwwO3",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-8",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, finance department, accounting, finance, investment, debt, grant funding, ",
    "Subsection": "86",
    "Question": "How many people work in Tulsa's municipal Finance Department? ",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's FY23 budget authorizes 161 full time positions",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recjQnxyXcDNu1ZfN",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-3, 1-3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, information technology, cybersecurity",
    "Subsection": "89-90",
    "Question": "How much does the City of Tulsa spend on its Information Technology Department?",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's FY23 budget includes $29.9 million for the IT Department. Their net budget increased by $3.1 million from FY22. Major changes in the IT department's FY23 budget includes: $1.1 million in salary increases, $287,000 to hire three new positions, $907,000 for the City's network security system, and $4.5 million to update or replace equipment. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "reckYDYnCl1CMNXVz",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-4",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, personnel, information technology, ",
    "Subsection": "91",
    "Question": "How many people work in Tulsa's IT Department? ",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's FY23 budget, authorizes 122 IT positions, all of which are full-time",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec24CIjbO5ots8sj",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-4",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, customer care center, ",
    "Subsection": "92",
    "Question": "Who can I call with questions or complaints regarding the City of Tulsa?",
    "Answer": "According to the City's website, Tulsa's 311 Customer Care call center bills itself as \"the central point of contact for the City of Tulsa.\" Available through call, text, and online chat, the service features English and Spanish-speaking live operators who screen and try to resolve calls, or forward them to the proper city department. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recvmWp2gCJz0dyFQ",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, customer care center, ",
    "Subsection": "93",
    "Question": "How much does Tulsa spend to operate its information call center? ",
    "Answer": "In FY23, Tulsa is budgeting $4 million dollars for its 311 Customer Care Center. The budget increased by 61% since FY22. The department is budgeting $663,000 to hire and train an additional 13 employees, including 10 operators, to deal with increased call volume. Officials also hope to address retention with $375,000 toward compensation adjustments. And the City is spending $120,000 on translation services. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recBLMMzhppTPc3PC",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, customer care center, personnel",
    "Subsection": "94",
    "Question": "How many people work in tulsa's information call center?",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's 311 Customer Care Center FY23 budget authorizes 57 full-time positions. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recFpY5q2ixrDXmuY",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, communications department, public service information, public relations",
    "Subsection": "95",
    "Question": "How does the City of Tulsa manage its media and public relations efforts?",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's Communications Department has the job of shaping how information about the city gets distributed to the public. That includes the traditional role of gathering information to provide to the press, interdepartmental communications, as well as social media/online content, and graphic design. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec1Bl2RMVGW8qCIi",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, communications department",
    "Subsection": "96",
    "Question": "How much does Tulsa spend on its Communications Department? ",
    "Answer": "The FY23 budget for Tulsa's Communication Department totals $824,000, a 26% increase from FY22. Budget documents attribute the increase to the need for increased messaging regarding COVID-19. The department is hiring a new graphics specialist at a $56,000 salary in order to meet that need. Existing salaries were also adjusted upward by $101,000 in order to address employee retention. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec8kWco9zuSJXRTt",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, communications department, personnel",
    "Subsection": "97",
    "Question": "How many people work in Tulsa's Communications Department? ",
    "Answer": "The FY23 budget for Tulsa's Communications Department authorizes 9 full-time positions. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recUSpakyR2c3zkQC",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, parking, facilities, asset management",
    "Subsection": "98",
    "Question": "What department oversee parking enforcement in Tulsa? ",
    "Answer": "Parking enforcement on streets and in public parking garages around Tulsa is overseen by the city's Asset Management Department. The same department is also responsible for repairing and installing parking meters, managing the city's fleet of vehicles,  managing real estate holdings, and providing security for those properties. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recKeFWYhMiifK3Wq",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-3, 1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, parking, facilities, asset management",
    "Subsection": "99-100",
    "Question": "How much does Tulsa spend on managing its assets and enforcing parking?",
    "Answer": "The FY23 budget for Tulsa's Asset Management Department totals $42 million, a 25% increase over FY22's budget. A third of that increase is attributable purely to higher gas prices. The City is also spending $2.6 million on improvements to One Technology Center,  and $1.4 million to improve Air Force Plant 3. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recyi6yZnZphohesl",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-3",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, parking, facilities, personnel",
    "Subsection": "101",
    "Question": "How many people work on parking enforcement and facility management for the City of Tulsa?",
    "Answer": "Tulsa's Asset Management Department employs 132 people as of FY23. That includes 30 building operations staff, 17 security staff, 67 equipment management staff, and 17 administration staff. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recSS95pggi3WPTbl",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "2",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, debt, bonds, general obligation, revenue, credit",
    "Subsection": "103",
    "Question": "What is the City of Tulsa's credit rating? ",
    "Answer": "According to the FY23 budget, general obligation bonds issued by Tulsa are rated in the top-tier of creditworthiness by national credit rating agencies. Standard and Poor's rates Tulsa's creditworthiness at AA, their third-highest ranking (only three American companies hold the highest rating). Moody's rates Tulsa at Aa1, their second-highest rating. Higher credit ratings imply less risk, meaning Tulsa is more likely to get favorable repayment terms when it needs to issue debt. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recsye8GxExffxYQ6",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, debt, bonds, revenue",
    "Subsection": "103",
    "Question": "How does Tulsa repay its debt? ",
    "Answer": "There are two major forms of debt available to Tulsa: general obligation bonds and revenue bonds. General obligation bonds can be used to finance a wide variety of projects and can be repaid using almost any form of revenue, although some states restrict how municipalities can service general obligation debt. In Tulsa, general obligation debt is paid off exclusively using a dedicated portion of property taxes. Revenue bonds are mainly used to finance projects (such as toll roads) that will generate revenue upon completion. Revenue bonds are guaranteed with anticipated future revenue from the project being financed. Strictly speaking, the City of Tulsa has never issued a revenue bond. However, authorities (such as the utilities authority) associated with Tulsa have issued revenue bonds that benefit the City as well. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "rec4YnysztlwyCvVg",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, debt, general obligation, bonds, debt service",
    "Subsection": "105",
    "Question": "How much debt does Tulsa have on its books?",
    "Answer": "As of June 30, 2022, the City of Tulsa's total debt liability is $395.3 million on general obligation bonds issued as early as 2013 and as recently as 2022. The cumulative debt originally incurred across all ten currently-active bonds equals $549.4 million. The average interest rate for those bonds is 2.75%. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recN7uHnGjNKE4aI9",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, debt, general obligation, bonds, debt service",
    "Subsection": "104",
    "Question": "How long will it take for Tulsa to pay down the debt it currently holds?",
    "Answer": "The City of Tulsa is currently liable for ten general obligation bonds (totaling $395.3 million) with varying maturity dates. According to FY23 budget documents, the City plans to satisfy all of its current debt by 2038. Over that timeframe, the City anticipates paying $49.4 million in interest, for a cumulative total debt service of $444.8 million. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "recptASFZQLI6g4c3",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "1-5",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "tulsa, budget, personnel, information technology, ",
    "Subsection": "108",
    "Question": "How many people are employed by the City of Tulsa across all its departments?",
    "Answer": "The City of Tulsa's FY23 budget authorizes 4,120 positions. The actual number of employees is subject to change. Almost 75% of positions are in public safety or transportation/public works. City-wide, 4,015 positions are considered full-time. Total staffing increased by 67 positions since FY22. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  },
  {
    "id": "rectQ3QkRoYunC0fu",
    "Source": "City of Tulsa Annual Budget FY 2022-2023",
    "Paragraph": "0",
    "Keywords (Enter into Concepts) copy": "program based budget",
    "Subsection": "111-140",
    "Question": "Does the City of Tulsa have a detailed breakdown of the costs to run its programs?",
    "Answer": "Yes. For the first time, Tulsa included a \"Program-Based\" budget as an appendix to its standard annual budget for FY23. The PBB, accessible here, provides approximate costs for virtually every program and service funded by the City of Tulsa. The PBB is useful because, in many cases, a single program may rely on collaboration from multiple City departments, making it difficult to calculate total funding from various department budgets. ",
    "Section": "4- Departments"
  }
]